<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ucosp Impressions on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/ucosp-impressions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ucosp Impressions on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 01:59:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/ucosp-impressions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Nikita wishes UofT made courses like UCOSP mandatory.</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/why-nikita-wishes-uoft-made-courses-like-ucosp-mandatory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 01:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/why-nikita-wishes-uoft-made-courses-like-ucosp-mandatory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--        @page { margin: 2cm }       P { margin-bottom: 0.21cm } --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Do not waste time being jealous: sometimes you&amp;#8217;re ahead, sometimes behind. Race is long and in the end you see that you are only competing with yourself&amp;#8221;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;he reason I switched from Mechanical Engineering to Computer Science after my first undergrad year, to be short: it was extremely boring. I did not want to wait for the 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; year to come in order  for the stuff to get more interesting. From the first two “project” courses in my undergrad I learnt zilch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;n CS program things were slightly better: some of the faculty members understood the importance of having a balance between theory, and, well, “cool stuff”. In our projects we imitated real software products, developed simple but very cool games (I still play my &amp;#8220;warehouse wars&amp;#8221; JavaScript game when I get bored of XBOX), learn how theory can be sometimes &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through;&#34;&gt;cool&lt;/span&gt; useful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;owever, one aspect was missing from my experience in all of my project / group CS courses: we were never taught to &lt;em&gt;make real decisions&lt;/em&gt; about &lt;em&gt;our own&lt;/em&gt; project&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Surely, we were awarded better marks for cleaner code. But as an example, in my second year we weren&amp;#8217;t allowed to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write your own socket writeln/readln methods in C. Rational: too complicated, you can&amp;#8217;t get it, it&amp;#8217;ll be hard for us [TA] to test it. Nobody cared that the provided methods were buggy 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design your own plugin system for your game: too complicated, you won&amp;#8217;t get it, it&amp;#8217;ll be hard for us to mark it. Well, assignment&amp;#8217;s implementation wasn&amp;#8217;t good at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with your own GUI: whaaat? are you insane? you have screenshots in your assignments 😛&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;ooks like a list of trivial tasks, but how much thinking, discussion, interaction can each single one of those promote? I&amp;#8217;d never thought I&amp;#8217;d have a chance to do those things at this university, but I am glad to know that I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;ot only UCOSP gave me a chance to meet my future colleagues in the field, but it also gave me a taste of what the real world responsibility is like. In short 2.5 days of the sprint I felt a lot of support both from the &amp;#8220;old survivors&amp;#8221; of the project and the new members like myself. I felt a healthy mix of responsibility and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; think UofT should consider making this course mandatory for students in CS specialist/major programs. I am sure UofT &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do that. If the don&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to, here is my &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;: I can confidently say that this year I learnt and will learn more about human interaction, project management, responsibility, code practices than in my 4 years of undergrad at UofT. I think that&amp;#8217;s worth something . It&amp;#8217;d be definitely a better investment than a second reading week in December. &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through;&#34;&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t read on vacations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kudos to all organizers, mentors, TAs, and students for making UCOSP possible!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;f you read until here, you are a hero 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short summary of the work done during UCOSP &amp;amp; plans:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I concentrated on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/&#34;&gt;Tickets page&lt;/a&gt; of Basie and on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/wiki/random-data-manpage-draft/&#34;&gt;random-data&lt;/a&gt; tool over these three days. I worked on &amp;amp; closed: &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#95&#34;&gt;95&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#90&#34;&gt;90&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#82&#34;&gt;82&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#73&#34;&gt;73&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through;&#34;&gt;Started converting Alex into Linux faith.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am planning to continue working on random-data, but I will give priority to the tickets assigned to me for &lt;strong&gt;0.6 Final&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#96&#34;&gt;96&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#96&#34;&gt;126&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://basieproject.org/stable/basie/basie/tickets/#96&#34;&gt;74&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>