<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fall 2010 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/categories/fall-2010/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fall 2010 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 20:38:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/categories/fall-2010/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>CoRAL project wrapping up for the semester</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/12/coral-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 20:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/12/coral-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A guest post by the CoRAL team.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this project was conceptualized and named in early October, we have made great strides in designing a user and application programming interface for visualizing activity on &lt;a href=&#34;http://hypatia.cs.ualberta.ca/ucospf10/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;CoRAL (Collaborative Review Analysis of Literature)&lt;/a&gt; and to be used in tandem with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/fab4browser/&#34;&gt;Fab4Browser&lt;/a&gt;. CoRAL/Fab4 is an academic publication browser that allows users to comment, discuss and annotate academic papers. It was designed to facilitate discussion and development of ideas and encourage collaboration and sharing of viewpoints between different experts of the scientific community. CoRAL (Collaborative Review Analysis of Literature) is a web tool to visualize these networks, gauging the activity and impact of a paper on CoRAL users, and measuring the usage data of specific users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCOSP students designed and implemented visualizations that could be used to analyze the popularity of a paper, highlight discussions about the paper, and display networks arising from these conversations. Furthermore, visualizations were implemented to measure a user’s activity on CoRAL, papers read, and papers annotated. To complete the project, we used a PHP logic tier to interact with the DB2 database, and several JavaScript frameworks to implement the interactive visualization widgets. Students were able to independently develop the back-end logic and the separate widgets, and collaboratively piece together their work into a single interactive web application. Students simultaneously learnt the practical use of PHP and JavaScript, visualization, and techniques in code communication and collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final product is a web tool that allows users to search for papers or other users on CoRAL and view information about the papers or users found. In the paper view, users are able to filter comments by the comment authors, and view on a timeline both when the paper was viewed and when comments were made. Furthermore, users can view the activity and popularity of users and comments based on comment ratings; user popularity and activity are visualized by their color and size on the network view. The person view displays both user activity and comments made on a timeline, and also displays a user’s interactivity with other users on a network graph. Furthermore, a summary of the user’s activity regarding papers read and comments made is displayed. The modular widgets can be adapted for use in other projects or pages involving CoRAL, or extended to display more complex analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In just a few months, we have successfully created a flexible tool to visualize usage information about CoRAL. In addition to measuring how CoRAL is used, information about papers and users is particularly valuable in realizing how certain scientific social networks are formed and whether certain ideas or people are influential or controversial. More importantly, it can be used to track the evolution of ideas or pieces of writing as they become more refined and possibly eventually publishable. We are currently in the process of refining the application, and documenting it with the hopes that it may be further developed in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board: &amp;#8220;So, where are we?&amp;#8221;</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/11/review-board-so-where-are-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 00:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/11/review-board-so-where-are-we/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted by Mike Conley on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2010/11/26/so-where-are-we/&#34;&gt;Review Board student blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following this blog, you’ll know that the team has been working very hard on their projects.  But I’ll bet those status reports can be a bit cryptic sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s my take on where we are so far, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hongbin has been working on an extension that will allow communication between Review Board and various bug-trackers.  Currently, his extension listens for events on Review Board (such as publishing a review request, publishing a review), and then alerts the appropriate issue/bug in the bug-tracker by posting a comment with a link to the review request.  Hongbin’s extension currently only works with Google Code projects, but will eventually be extended to other bug-trackers as well (Bugzilla, Github’s issue tracker, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laila has put together a new version of the Windows Review Board installer.  The installer is responsible for making sure a Windows machine has everything it needs in order to get an instance of Review Board up and running.  Laila is also working on a project that will allow review requests to have files attached to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lindsey and Brendan have been putting together an impressive suite of client tools to interact with the new Review Board API.  The monolithic “post-review” script will, I believe, be eventually modified to use these scripts.  The scripts are also designed to be easily imported, so that developers can write their own tools to interact with Review Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lianne has been working on an extension that will give Review Board WebHook notification abilities.  This means that, when various events happen on Review Board, the extension can send a request to a remote server to trigger another action.  Example:  when a review request has been marked as submitted, the Webhook might signal a script that publishes a notification to Twitter, or to an IRC bot, or to an RSS feed, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kevin has completed his “collapsible-reviews” project: for review requests with a long series of reviews/revisions, we can save on vertical screen real-estate by automatically collapsing the reviews that have been read.  Kevin has also implemented a one-click Ship-It function, which makes easy reviews even easier.  Kevin is now working on the designs for a new user profile page for Review Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Basie/Pinax team has been up to.</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/11/what-the-basiepinax-team-has-been-up-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 16:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/11/what-the-basiepinax-team-has-been-up-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A guest post by team member Todd Ritchie.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Basie/Pinax team has been working on a mailing list module for the next iteration of Basie. This module was designed with the intent of being able to decouple it from Basie and use it with any Pinax application. We started from scratch and during the code sprint we managed to get creation of mailing lists working, addition of subscribed e-mail lists, and walking of subscribed e-mails so that we can send messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been busy since then and have met on Wednesday mornings on the basie IRC channel. We have a team of four so voting doesn’t always work since there can be an even split. We’ve implemented a rotating position of dictator-for-the-week who has the final say on issues so we can proceed quickly. Recently we’ve decided to meet on Thursday evenings as well. Since the code sprint we have implemented receiving of mail with the help of a procmail script, better views for management of subscribers and mailing lists, verification of e-mail addresses, parsing and storing of incoming mail, and a first attempt at sending mail. Everyone has had the chance to move back and forth between different parts of the MVC model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the code sprint Kyle and Todd started with the database back end and the first template. Lance and Joel began with the mail parser. The pairs then swapped to Joel and Kyle working on the parser and Lance and Todd working on the subscription datamodel and management. Kyle integrated the mail receiver with our script and mangled strings for the parser, Todd and Lance have swapped who’s worked on views versus who’s working on templates and Joel has focused on the parser as well and sending mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge we faced most recently is working out the best way to send mail. We have essentially three choices as outlined in our &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/basie/mailrelay/issue/19/create-send-methods-for-listmessage-and&#34;&gt;mail sending ticket&lt;/a&gt;. The latest stable version of Pinax does provide an API for sending mail, but it does not allow you to add headers. The development version of Pinax has a new function that allows you to add your own headers. We could create our own mailer, but then we would have to maintain two mailers since the library we use for e-mail address verification relies on the Pinax mailer. Between these three choices we’ve decided to go with the latest development version of Pinax rather than do without essential mailing list headers or maintain or own mailer code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next steps are to migrate to a newer version of the Pinax library so that we can modify headers while sending mail, to improve our existing list management templates, to write templates and views to read archived mail (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/basie/mailrelay/issue/20/create-views-for-accessing-archived-email&#34;&gt;ticket #20&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/basie/mailrelay/issue/23/create-templates-for-accessing-archived&#34;&gt;ticket #23&lt;/a&gt;), and to polish what we’ve got.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We intend to enter a feature freeze after these features have been implemented and work on improving the installation process, create external documentation, make sure that our tests have adequate coverage, and make sure that our code conforms to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinaxproject.com/docs/dev/contributing.html#coding-style&#34;&gt;Pinax style guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest post: an update from the POSIT project</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/guest-post-an-update-from-the-posit-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 02:13:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/guest-post-an-update-from-the-posit-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://posit.hfoss.org/&#34;&gt;POSIT&lt;/a&gt; aims to create a portable, opensource tool for the Android platform to aid search and rescue efforts by allowing the transmission of data between users and to central servers. Mentor Ralph Morelli provided this update:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things are going very well with the POSIT group. The students have now all identified appropriate projects and each is making steady progress on their work. We have been meeting every Thursday for a brief Skype conference during which we discuss any issues that come up. The students have been very good about solving problems on their own and helping each other with ideas and suggestions. In addition they are also vetting each other&amp;#8217;s bug fixes, which will help us resolve some of the outstanding issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is a brief summary of what the students in the POSIT group have taken on for their capstone projects. We will be tracking their contributions and their progress through POSIT&amp;#8217;s issues tracker on the Google code repository. See issues 84-90 here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edward Bassett (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/issues/detail?id=84&#34;&gt;Issue #84&lt;/a&gt;) will design and development an enhancement to the FindActivity that will directly allow the selected Find to be displayed on a Map. The Find will be centered on the Map. Edward has made several updates to the repository including to some of the tutorial (Wiki) pages. Edward has now acquired an Android phone and has done some good debugging of the Tracker module, which led to a bug fix in the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greg Knox (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/issues/detail?id=86&#34;&gt;Issue #86&lt;/a&gt;) will design and develop a search and/or sort feature to the ListFindsActivity. Similar to the search feature in the phone&amp;#8217;s Contacts Activity, this will allow the user to more easily locate a specific Find within a long list of Finds. Greg has completed a good portion of the server-side implementation and is now working on the client side code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yang Ha (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/issues/detail?id=87&#34;&gt;Issue #87&lt;/a&gt;) will design and develop a fix a defect in the SyncFindsActivity whereby synchronization is not performed correctly on changes to finds after before T for Project A if that user had already synced the phone on Project B after time T. He has proposed a design for a revised Synchronization algorithm, which he is now implementing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derek Bachelor (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/issues/detail?id=89&#34;&gt;Issue #89&lt;/a&gt;) will design and develop a menu for the MapFindsActivity. Among other features, the menu will allow the user to center the map on the user&amp;#8217;s current location or on a specific Find. Derek has proposed a nice design that includes several new features for the MapFindsActivity. He is now in the process of implementing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anna Kournava (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/posit-mobile/issues/detail?id=90&#34;&gt;Issue #90&lt;/a&gt;) will design and develop a Bluetooth based sync feature for the ListFindsActivity that will enable two phones to synchronize their Finds directly rather than by downloading them through the Server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guest post: an update from the CoRAL team</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/guest-post-an-update-from-the-coral-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2010 02:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/guest-post-an-update-from-the-coral-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The CoRAL team (formerly known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/fab4browser&#34;&gt;fab4&lt;/a&gt;) has been making great progress on our task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The task is to develop a visualization service for the fab4 browser project, whose objective is to support communities of readers by allowing them to share their comments on the documents they read. The original fab4 project simply provides a canvas on which to place and view annotations of different types on a document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our work, we assume that the fab4 user community consists of researchers either reviewing papers for the purpose of writing surveys and related-research sections of new publications or for the purpose of accepting/rejecting papers submitted to a conference. For that reason, we are extending the fab4 concept of comments and annotations with polarity (likes/dislikes notes) and we support comments as responses to comments, since literature reviewing is a fundamentally a discourse task. Correspondingly, the CoRAL extension, which is the task of the UCOSP team, is designed to visualize the activity of the community so that they can perceive intuitively who is reading what papers, what the readers think of the papers they read, what papers are being read recently and/or frequently, what papers are generally agreed upon to be &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; and which ones cause more disagreement among their readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we have developed (a) a general framework around a container of visualizations supported by a set of data-retrieval and layout utilities, and (b) a set of specific interactive visualizations to illustrate the social network implicit in the fab4 community and the communication threads around papers. We are working on a temporal visualization of reviewing activity around a paper and on a person-centric visualization reporting on one’s papers of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapshots of the interface will be coming soon, but in the mean time, please let us know (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ucospf10@hypatia.cs.ualberta.ca&#34;&gt;ucospf10@hypatia.cs.ualberta.ca&lt;/a&gt;) what else you think CoRAL should be supporting, or, more generally, what we should be thinking about. You can see what we are up to at &lt;a href=&#34;http://hypatia.cs.ualberta.ca/ucospf10/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&#34;&gt;http://hypatia.cs.ualberta.ca/ucospf10/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:stroulia@ualberta.ca&#34;&gt;Eleni Stroulia&lt;/a&gt; on behalf of Samaneh Bayat, Ilia Pak, Chong Su, Jia Sun and Keen Sung.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall semester code sprint — it&amp;#8217;s a wrap!</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/ucosp-code-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 15:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall2010/2010/10/ucosp-code-sprint/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This weekend, over 50 students and project mentors gathered in Toronto for this semester&amp;#8217;s code sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6460.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-2782&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6460&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6460.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6460.jpg 846w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6460-300x198.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 846px) 100vw, 846px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why go through all the trouble and expense of bringing students together to a single physical location to work on their projects? Isn&amp;#8217;t the point of UCOSP to teach students to work in a distributed environment? Yes, but from experience, we&amp;#8217;ve found that when teams are able to meet even once, the odds of success are dramatically increased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many, remotely collaborating with teammates, a mentor, or mailing list is intimidating, especially for the many students who&amp;#8217;ve never worked in a distributed fashion before. Getting together at the code sprint leads to smoother interactions in the future. It&amp;#8217;s also a great chance to meet other students and industry contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6502.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-2778 alignnone&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6502&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6502.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6502.jpg 846w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6502-300x200.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 846px) 100vw, 846px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code sprint also marks the point in the semester where students decide on goals for the remaining two months of the semester. Now that environments are set up and the code bases are explored, students can now move forward and accomplish a meaningful chunk of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6490.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2779&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6490&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6490-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6490-300x200.jpg 300w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6490.jpg 846w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Friday morning (apologies to our Pacific Standard Time students!) until Sunday noon, students got remaining environment kinks sorted out, discussed tools and strategies for their projects, negotiated scope, and began their work on their goals. After these two and a half days of work, what got done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://posit.hfoss.org/&#34;&gt;POSIT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Portable Open Search and Identification Tool) ****is a mobile app for the Android platform that enables disaster relief workers to capture and send back &lt;em&gt;finds&lt;/em&gt; from the field&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; Besides being able to play around with the application on handsets that mentor Ralph Morelli brought along, the team fixed some outstanding bugs (and found some new ones) and submitted their first patches. They also scoped out tasks for the remainder of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ingres.com/&#34;&gt;Ingres&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an open-source relational database; the team will be focusing on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.ingres.com/wiki/IngresGeospatial&#34;&gt;geospational components&lt;/a&gt;. With its four million lines of code and years of development, the biggest challenge for students was setting up a working build environment. With this hurdled cleared, the focus for the next two months will be adding different output formats and working on documentation and testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6479.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2780&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6479&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6479-300x200.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6479-300x200.jpg 300w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6479.jpg 846w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basie on Pinax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s goal is to take components of Basie, a web-based software project forge, and rebuilding them on top of Pinax, a collection of reusable apps for Django. With a version control application almost finished, the next goal will be adding a mailing list feature to Pinax. Over the weekend, the team went from nothing to &amp;#8220;we can send mail!&amp;#8221; and will be tackling access control features next. You can follow the group&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/&#34;&gt;progress on their blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fosslc.org/drupal/freeseer&#34;&gt;Freeseer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; project produces a video capture utility capable of capturing presentations. Over the weekend, the team almost finished a new internationalization component and fixed some filesystem-related bugs. Next up: adding live streaming support and packaging the project for different Linux distributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/fab4browser/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;fab4browser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a tool to collaboratively annotate files and there is a demand to gather and display analytics. Since this team&amp;#8217;s project isn&amp;#8217;t quite on the fab4browser project but a tool that uses it, the first task was coming up with a new name. The team settled on &amp;#8220;CORAL&amp;#8221;, short for &amp;#8220;collaborative review analysis of literature.&amp;#8221; Over the weekend, the team picked the tools that they&amp;#8217;ll be using, tested visualization tools, and divided up the future work between the PHP back-end, the middle tier, and the visualization functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6680.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-2777&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6680&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6680-300x173.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;173&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6680-300x173.jpg 300w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6680.jpg 846w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reviewboard.org/&#34;&gt;Review Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful web-based tool designed to &amp;#8216;take the pain out of code review.&amp;#8217; On the weekend, the team worked on integrating the post-commit workflow, solidifying the third-party extension framework, and shiny new tools for using the new web API. Future projects include work on an easy-to-use Windows installer, and usability updates to the web interface. You can follow their progress &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;on the team blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://markusproject.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a grading and code review tool that gives the flexibility of pen-on-paper marking through the web. One week before the code sprint, the Markus project was &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/MarkUsProject/Markus&#34;&gt;moved over to Github&lt;/a&gt; so part of the code sprint weekend was spent on adjusting to the new git workflow. Students also fixed some bugs and made their first patches. Sub-groups will be working on the two goals for this semester: adding an automated testing framework (students can run tests on their code; instructors can automatically test submissions) and building report generation tools. You can follow their progress on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.markusproject.org/&#34;&gt;the team&amp;#8217;s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sourceforge.net/projects/db2mc/&#34;&gt;Technology Explorer for IBM DB2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a web-based tool that is a teaching tool for users new to DB2. This weekend was the first real chance to really play around with the codebase and the team was able to finish a few small projects. For the remainder of the semester, they&amp;#8217;ll be working on some requests that came from the project&amp;#8217;s users: improving the tool&amp;#8217;s scripting language and adding reporting and exporting functionality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6464.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-2781&#34; title=&#34;IMG_6464&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6464.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; srcset=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6464.jpg 846w, http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/IMG_6464-300x200.jpg 300w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 846px) 100vw, 846px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and-a-word-from-our-sponsors:ea4b8d973cac0334af7105c1da15ef29&#34;&gt;And a word from our sponsors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without sponsor support, doing a code sprint with all UCOSP students would be impossible. Thanks again to Google, O&amp;#8217;Reilly, the Canadian Association of Computer Science Chairs, the Jonah Group, and Research in Motion for your support!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>