<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fall 2012 on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/categories/fall-2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fall 2012 on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 12:45:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/categories/fall-2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry HTML5 wraps up</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/12/blackberry-html5-wraps-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 12:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/12/blackberry-html5-wraps-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Yan from UBC posts his &lt;a href=&#34;http://devblog.blackberry.com/2012/12/ucosp-end-of-term-results-part-2/&#34;&gt;final report&lt;/a&gt; from this term&amp;#8217;s UCOSP project. Tim Windsor, the Blackberry HTML5 mentor also joins in with a final overview from the term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackberry HTML5 Team Wraps Up (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/12/blackberry-html5-team-wraps-up-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 10:19:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/12/blackberry-html5-team-wraps-up-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Clarke of Laurentian University gives his final wrap-up of his UCOSP &lt;a href=&#34;http://devblog.blackberry.com/2012/12/ucosp-end-of-term-results-part-1/&#34;&gt;work this term&lt;/a&gt; with the Blackberry HTML5 team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Update from the Blackberry Team</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/11/midterm-update-from-the-blackberry-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 20:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/11/midterm-update-from-the-blackberry-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://devblog.blackberry.com/2012/11/ucosp-midterm-update/&#34;&gt;midterm update&lt;/a&gt; is now available from the Blackberry HTML5 team, featuring work from Hidaya Sekkal from the University of Ottawa and Arman Fallah from the University of British Columbia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board Check-in</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/review-board-check-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 12:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/review-board-check-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John Sintal from UofT &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2012/10/16/ucosp-blog-post-5/&#34;&gt;checks in&lt;/a&gt; with how his term is progressing with the Review Board team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Week in the Life of Review Board</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/a-week-in-the-life-of-review-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 21:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/a-week-in-the-life-of-review-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tina Yang from UBC provides a glimpse into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/ucosp-blog-post-4/&#34;&gt;week in the life&lt;/a&gt; of the Review Board project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blackberry HTML5 Team Gets Started</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/the-blackberry-html5-team-gets-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 15:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/the-blackberry-html5-team-gets-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rimdevblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ucosp-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bb github&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Windsor, the Blackberry HTML5 mentor, sends &lt;a href=&#34;http://devblog.blackberry.com/2012/10/ucosp-program/&#34;&gt;an update&lt;/a&gt; on the team&amp;#8217;s initial sprint at Communitech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code sprint summary</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/code-sprint-summary-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 14:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/code-sprint-summary-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UCOSP 2012 is off and running following a successful code sprint in Kitchener Waterloo last weekend.  We have 58 students from 16 different Canadian universities working on 8 projects this term and from everything I saw and heard, the sprint was a great success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UCOSP program operates under the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cacsaic.org&#34;&gt;Canadian Association of Computer Science&lt;/a&gt; (CACS/AIC).  Michelle Craig, chair of the UCOSP steering committee, attended the CACS/AIC Chairs meeting in the spring and once again promoted the program, so we are able to welcome even more universities to the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cs.uwaterloo.ca/~rtholmes/&#34;&gt;Reid Holmes&lt;/a&gt;, a member of the steering committee, made all the local arrangements in Kitchener Waterloo, and in particular, connected with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.communitech.ca&#34;&gt;Communitech&lt;/a&gt; who allowed us to use the Hub for the sprint. They were excellent hosts, and it was a real pleasure to work in such a great space.  The Communitech Hub is in the same building as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/about/jobs/locations/waterloo/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; office, and we were treated to a tour of the office, lightning talks about open source projects at Google, and a fabulous lunch.  Google is our primary sponsor for the fall sprint, so were especially grateful that they were willing to give us a tour and feed us as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, it was great to see the buzz in the rooms as the students got to know each other and their mentors, and began to really wrap their heads around their projects. We are very fortunate to have great mentors participate in the program, and this year we had a record 4 mentors who were once UCOSP students themselves.  Thanks for coming back!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.toronto.edu/~reid/&#34;&gt;I&amp;#8217;m&lt;/a&gt; both a member of the steering committee and the project mentor for MarkUs. This term the MarkUs project members come from seven universities in five time time zones: UBC, University of Alberta, University of Manitoba, University of Waterloo, University of Toronto, L&amp;#8217;Université Sherbrooke, and Dalhousie University.  Needless to say, it is a challenge to find a common meeting time! Nevertheless, the enthusiasm of the team members and their willingness to just dive in is great to see!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope everyone has a great term!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MarkUs team at the sprint</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/markus-team-at-the-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 13:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/markus-team-at-the-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started on Thursday evening when we flew into the quaint city of Kitchener.  I quickly met up with some other UCOSP students and we all headed to the Delta to sleep off the plane ride over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bright and early on Friday we all met up for some breakfast buffet and walked over to CommuniTech for some really fun ice-breaker games where of course we paralleled processed our way to a win! It was great to finally meet everyone face to face, and learn all about everyone’s weird/unique talents. Next Karen gave us an overview of MarkUs and how the application is used, and what sorts of bugs are currently ongoing. Having a perspective on the product will definitely help when developing fixes for MarkUs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half way through the day we had a great break with the Google crew upstairs.  They were nice enough to show us their slide, cool chairs, and hidey holes for napping as well as giving a pretty cool talk on open-source technologies happening at Google.  The talk including topics on Chromium, PyCon and Cordova. It’s inspiring to see a company who wants to make the quality of the internet better in every way, and who sponsors university students such as ourselves to gain experience on open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the afternoon we all took on a small task to work on so that we could make sure all of us knew the correct process for taking on development work, submitting it to be reviewed, and merged. There were many questions about git, rails, and ruby that were asked and answered.&amp;lt;/ That night we went out for a team (missing Mina and Karen) dinner and drink (see picture below). On Saturday, some of the team worked with Byron on the testing framework. Since I wasn’t on that part of the team I’ll provide a picture of their overall design but not an explanation, which I’m sure someone can write a much better blog post on. For the rest of the day it was more of the same. I finally was able to issue a Pull Request, and I think in total our team was able to get (at least!) a dozen Pull Requests in this weekend. Overall, the code sprint was a great success! I think we all came away with a much better idea of what MarkUs is designed to do, and how it is built. Definitely a huge thanks to all the coordinators for organizing, and a special one to Google for making it happen. &amp;ndash; Kira McCoan (UBC student, MarkUs project member)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#39;gallery-4&#39; class=&#39;gallery galleryid-2887 gallery-columns-3 gallery-size-thumbnail&#39;&gt;
  &lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;http://ucosp.ca/fall-2012/2012/10/markus-team-at-the-sprint/attachment/imag0456/&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMAG0456-150x150.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;IMAG0456&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;dl class=&#39;gallery-item&#39;&gt;
    &lt;dt class=&#39;gallery-icon landscape&#39;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#39;http://ucosp.ca/fall-2012/2012/10/markus-team-at-the-sprint/attachment/img_20120930_104801/&#39;&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/IMG_20120930_104801-150x150.jpeg&#34; class=&#34;attachment-thumbnail size-thumbnail&#34; alt=&#34;IMG_20120930_104801&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br style=&#39;clear: both&#39; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board&amp;#8217;s Fall 2012 Sprint</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/review-boards-fall-2012-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 16:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/fall-2012/2012/10/review-boards-fall-2012-sprint/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Jesus Zambrano from Review Board writes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-1-intro-and-expectations-for-the-semester:45b29a675c58700839036d3d014224de&#34;&gt;Part 1- Intro and expectations for the semester:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi there, I am Jesus Zambrano and I’m a 4th year Software Engineering student at university Of Ottawa. I first heard about UCOSP through e-mail. Once I started reading about it I got really excited and decided to join UCOSP. I really liked the idea of working in a distributed team with students from other schools. In case you didn’t know, UCOSP organizes a code sprint per semester. At the sprint, students and their mentors gather and work on their assigned projects. This year’s sprint took place in Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project that I’m going to be working on is Review Board, a web-based tool that eases the code-review process for developers. More specifically, my task within Review Board will be to reduce the number of full-page reloads to move towards dynamic updating of the page content. I’m new to some of the technologies used at Review Board, but I’m hoping my effort will make up for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect this experience to be challenging but very rewarding in the end. I think it is a great way to really prove your self and show what you are capable of as a starting developer. This will be my first time working on a project where my input will potentially have an impact on real customers. It will be very fulfilling to see that my work has helped someone in some way. Which is really the essence of this profession, solving people’s problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;part-2-thoughts-on-the-sprint:45b29a675c58700839036d3d014224de&#34;&gt;Part 2-Thoughts on the sprint:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code sprint at Waterloo was a great experience. The mentors are extremely helpful and know how to walk students through their problems. They do a really good job at motivating you to work hard (you don’t get your ship-it shirt until you fix your first bug!). I also enjoyed the environment we worked in; everyone was laid back and had a good sense of humor. But at the same time we were very serious about our work and getting things done. With Review Board, you really get a sense that we are all a group that is there to learn from each other as much as possible. For anyone reading this that is considering joining UCSOP, do it! You will have a great time. Thank you Steven, Mike, David and Christian for helping us and for your commitment to UCOSP!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>