<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bios on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/categories/bios/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bios on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 19:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/categories/bios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Basie Status Updates</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/basie-status-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2010 19:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/basie-status-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re on track to release Version 0.6 in time for &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.pycon.org/2010/about/&#34;&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt; (which is three weeks away), though we may get there by slapping the word &amp;#8220;beta&amp;#8221; after the &amp;#8220;0.6&amp;#8221; :-). Lots of bugs are being fixed; the ticketing system and milestone display are seeing significant re-work; and we&amp;#8217;re cleaning up code (e.g., pulling Javascript out of HTML pages and putting it in separate files, doing better error reporting). More importantly (at least for me), our work now has a rhythm: stuff is going up on &lt;a href=&#34;http://review.basieproject.org/dashboard/&#34;&gt;ReviewBoard&lt;/a&gt;, getting checked, and getting committed on a pretty regular basis. We do have a couple of big things to worry about&amp;#8212;grabbing IRC messages sometimes puts a strangely high load on the CPU, for example, and the search index file sometimes locks up&amp;#8212;but we&amp;#8217;re getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1957&#34;&gt;Chad Cogar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1931&#34;&gt;François Fournier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1961&#34;&gt;Jackie Huynh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1975&#34;&gt;Maciej Kozlowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1953&#34;&gt;Alex Le&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1927&#34;&gt;Nikita Pchelin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1899&#34;&gt;Guillaume Simard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1905&#34;&gt;Chris van Wiermeesch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.basieproject.org/?p=1965&#34;&gt;Veronica Wong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jean Lalande</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/jean-lalande/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 03:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/jean-lalande/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m Jean (or John, as you like) and I&amp;#8217;ll be working on the Data Center Flight Simulator. I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year student in software engineering at Université Laval and that&amp;#8217;s my last semester, which is great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like several students here, that&amp;#8217;ll be my first experience in an open-source project and it&amp;#8217;ll certainly be a new challenge for me. The reason I&amp;#8217;m here is because I wanted to work on something different for my last school&amp;#8217;s project. That should do the job!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main interests are software architecture, project management and security, but I&amp;#8217;m always looking for something new to learn. The last project I&amp;#8217;ve been working on was a video game that is using a webcam as a controller. The part about computer vision was really nice to learn and use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s about it See you all this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guillaume Simard</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/guillaume-simard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 16:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/guillaume-simard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Guillaume Simard ( pronounced &amp;#8216; &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.merriam-webster.com/soundc11/bix/bixgui03.wav&#34;&gt;Giiyom&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8216; ), I&amp;#8217;m currently doing my last semester at Université Laval in Software Engineering ( sounds much better than &amp;#8216; Génie Logiciel &amp;#8216; .. ! ). These last four years, I&amp;#8217;ve worked mostly on web applications and video game development ( a hobby of mine ). I like using Python, which is part of why I chose Basie as my last project for my degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really looking forward to meeting you during the weekend ! I haven&amp;#8217;t had the chance to see Toronto before and meeting fellow developers is always a great experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcel Guzman</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/marcel-guzman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 07:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/marcel-guzman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all! My name is Marcel Guzman and I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year student at SFU. My interests lie in online development of all kinds (from low-level networking to high-level web app&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cake.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1998&#34; title=&#34;Marcel Guzman&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cake.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34; height=&#34;266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;s and everything in between!). I also enjoy esoteric languages as well as operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This semester, I&amp;#8217;ll be working on Thunderbird. I&amp;#8217;m very interested in Mozilla projects as well as learning how to code desktop apps so I think it will be a great fit for me. I&amp;#8217;ve previously worked as a co-op with Electronic Arts (Sports Online) and SAP (Crystal Reports Server), both of which were primarily C++ jobs. When I&amp;#8217;m not coding, I enjoy board games, skiing, and as pictured, nomming delicious cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the upcoming sprint&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sylvain Petitclerc</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/sylvain-petitclerc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2010 03:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/sylvain-petitclerc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1986&#34; style=&#34;width: 145px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/dsc01665.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1986&#34; title=&#34;Sylvain Petitclerc&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/dsc01665.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;135&#34; height=&#34;180&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Sylvain Petitclerc
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Sylvain. I&amp;#8217;m from the Université Laval, Québec city. This is my last miles to graduate as a software engineer. I will work on Data Center Flight Simulator for this semester. I think that UCOSP will be a great experience to live. I&amp;#8217;m really interested to learn and ready to solve problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m excited to see everyone this week end in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denis Lila</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/denis-lila/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2010 03:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/denis-lila/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Denis. I&amp;#8217;m a third year computer science (AI) at the University of Toronto. I will be working with the Mercurial team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose the Mercurial project because I didn&amp;#8217;t want to be involved in any academia-related projects, and I wanted to work on something with a large number of users. Also, C and python are my favourite languages, and it is sponsored by Fog Creek Software, which seems like a great company, so it would be nice to get on their good side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as programming experience goes, I don&amp;#8217;t have much outside of school related things. Pertaining to school, the best non math course I&amp;#8217;ve taken so far is, without a doubt, Operating Systems. Currently, my most interesting courses (other than this) are natural language processing, intro. to AI, and intro. to visual computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to the sprint this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chad Cogar</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/chad-cogar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 20:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/chad-cogar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/chad.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-full wp-image-1974&#34; title=&#34;Chad Cogar&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/chad.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;164&#34; height=&#34;222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey Everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Chad Cogar and I&amp;#8217;m a fourth (fifth? :S) year student at the University of Toronto. My interests lie primarily in systems programming and artificial intelligence, and my experience stems mostly from personal projects (video game and mod development, various web projects) and coursework (CSC369: Operating Systems &amp;#8211; best CS course ever?). My favorite languages are C++ and Python, but I&amp;#8217;ve worked extensively with others as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the realm of CS, I&amp;#8217;m a Psych Specialist and just recently applied to law school. Over the past few years I&amp;#8217;ve also been heavily involved in student life at the college level, particularly student government (hence the extra year of undergrad).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to spending my last semester working with a number of you on the Basie Project, and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to meet all of you next weekend! 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Chad&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Chow</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/henry-chow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 12:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/henry-chow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://hkchow.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cimg2001-sep1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;CIMG2001-sep&#34; src=&#34;http://hkchow.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cimg2001-sep1.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;170&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Hey all! My name is Henry. I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year computer science student at the University of British Columbia. I am also minoring in Commerce. My interests lies in the e-commerce field, such as creating bank applications and websites. I have a good knowledge in Java, SQL, VBA and HTML. I have worked at MDA, Nokia, Quartz Imaging, and HSBC in my previous co-op job placements. I look forward to meeting all of you!
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joseph Mate</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/joseph-mate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2010 17:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/joseph-mate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1958&#34; style=&#34;width: 235px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignright&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/dsc01630.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-medium wp-image-1958&#34; title=&#34;jmate&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/dsc01630.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;Joseph Mate&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Joseph Mate
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Joseph. I am in 3B Computer Science at the University of Waterloo and will be working with MarkUs this term. I have not worked an open source project before; however, I am eager to start. I have lots of experience with Java from school and work. I have a little experience with C#, Python and Unix Shell Programming. I recently started playing around with Ruby and this term will be an excellent opportunity to extend what I already know. On my free time, I work on a flashcard application for my desktop and android to help me learn vocabulary in other languages. It&amp;#8217;s extremely convenient when I am on the go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interests outside of Computer Science include: Indoor Rock Climbing, Judo, and Languages ( Hungarian, Spanish and Mandarin ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miles Billsman</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/miles-billsman/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 16:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/miles-billsman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there, I&amp;#8217;m Miles and I&amp;#8217;ll be working on Eclipse IDE for Education project. I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to learning about working on open-source projects and the Eclipse GUI framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/miles-bw-by-pete-on-fuji-241x351.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1949&#34; title=&#34;Miles Billsman&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/miles-bw-by-pete-on-fuji-241x351.jpg?w=205&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;205&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8230; I feel like I&amp;#8217;m writing a dating profile &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;I like moonlit walks on the beach and death metal bands that dress up like goblins.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year student at University of Toronto so I&amp;#8217;ll be graduating and getting a jobby-job shortly. I&amp;#8217;m interested in HCI, artificial intelligence and computer graphics. I did a project course for something called PySpection this summer. It is a visual debugger for Python aimed at first year students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous life before returning to school I was a graphic designer doing packaging for beer, cigarettes and pharmaceuticals among other things. If there was a way that packaging could encourage you to enter a downward spiral, we were there. So if you need something to look good let me know, I may be able to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, Miles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatima-Zohra Cherkaoui</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/fatima-zohra-cherkaoui/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/fatima-zohra-cherkaoui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Fatima-Zohra Cherkaoui, I’m a junior (3rd year) from Minnesota State University, majoring in Software engineering. I will be working on the Pony-Build project for the upcoming semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited to take part in this open-source project which will be for sure an inspiring learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, I have been using mostly C-related languages C++ and Java, but I have lately learned a functional language “Scala” (used in Twitter) and “Boo” (a Python-like language) which has given me the chance to broaden my view on programming from the traditional imperative style to the functional one. I’m passionate about new technologies and enjoy particularly software design and solving challenging problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the UCOSP is an excellent initiative and can’t wait to meet you all 😉&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Laite</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/max-laite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/max-laite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, Max here, I am a Senior in the Computer Science department at the University of the Virgin Islands. I will be working on pony-build for the Winter Semester. I dabble in bits and pieces of everything, hoping to get back into, and refine, my Python this semester while working on the Pony-Build project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to meeting everyone at the Code Sprint next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Khushboo Shakya</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/01/khushboo-shakya/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2010 21:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/01/khushboo-shakya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Khushboo Shakya and I am from Minnesota State University majoring in Software Engineering with a minor in Mathematics. I will be working with the Pony-Build team. I am pretty much a newbie! I have worked on small group projects for school and few outside school but not a huge one like this. So I am utterly nervous but excited at the same time to work on this project. I look forward to meeting everyone in Toronto!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Khushboo&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Veronica Wong</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/veronica-wong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 17:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/veronica-wong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Veronica, and I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year student at UofT finishing up my undergraduate degree in computer science (specializing in software engineering and minoring in economics). I&amp;#8217;ll be working on the usability and interface design aspect of Basie for the upcoming term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate enough to work with Professor Karen Reid on MarkUs last Spring on its design, and with Khai Truong with his research project on upcycling and disposable technology the same summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I&amp;#8217;m 6-months into my year-long internship at Isobar as an information architect/user experience designer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to meeting you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nikita Pchelin</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/nikita-pchelin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 00:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/01/nikita-pchelin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/10622_820515184112_28133045_51825249_3302346_n.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft size-medium wp-image-1888&#34; style=&#34;border:1px solid black;margin:5px;&#34; title=&#34;pic&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/10622_820515184112_28133045_51825249_3302346_n.jpg?w=225&#34; alt=&#34;Nikita Pchelin&#34; width=&#34;225&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hi guys, my name is Nikita Pchelin and this semester I will be working on Basie. Last semester I worked on ElmCity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a 3rd year CS and French student, at the University of Toronto (Mississauga campus). I am really excited about taking this course – partly because if the programming challenges, but also because I want to experience working in a large team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in a team where members live thousand miles away from each other is challenging; it forces the members to find new effective ways of interaction to get things done in time. I’d like to learn more about this, and this course seems to be an excellent opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck to all students who are taking this course, and lots of patience to our mentors! :]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(to be honest, this is almost exactly what I wrote in the last semester&amp;#8217;s introduction. But hey, at least I changed the picture)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>