<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ingres on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/categories/ingres/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ingres on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 01:20:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/categories/ingres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry&amp;#039;s Midway Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/03/henrys-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 01:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/03/henrys-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never worked on an open-source project before, it has proven to be challenging for me to run different scripts and commands in an open-source environment. It has been a huge learning curve for me to adjust to open-source programs when I was babied all these years by GUI applications and Windows. Although we are half-way through the term, we still have a lot of development work to do. The setup of the environment took awhile as there are so many configurations that are required for this project. Yet, it was worthwhile as I’ve learned a lot from creating environment variables to running scripts on maven, and then configuring build path in installing SVN for file sharing in Eclipse. Setting up and running maven, GeoTools and GeoServer were both challenging and time-consuming as making a tiny mistake would require hours of work to fix. Yet, I have no regrets or concerns because I have learned a lot through this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, we are in the progress of connecting to the Ingres database server, where we will be running our testing. Once that is set up, the remaining tasks will be mostly development, which should not be too difficult. I had not anticipated setting up the environment can be so difficult and time-consuming. Nevertheless, Andrew, other members in the team and the open-source community have been very helpful. In the Ingres team, we are assigned to different mailing lists where important information is communicated across. There is also documentation regarding geospatial data that we need to read and understand for our development. Thus, considerable time is spent on reading and catching up each week. I had spent around 8-10 hours each week on reading mailing lists, catching up, and providing my input to the project. It is longer than I anticipated, but it is worthwhile as it gives me an idea of what it’s like working in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although impediments slowed us down, I feel that we can make up for it now that we have much of our set up completed. Much of the remaining tasks are development, which I am comfortable with. I learned that communication is very important especially when all of us are scattered across Canada. As long as I ask questions, I will always get the help I need. Weekly meeting and status updates are very helpful in sharing our knowledge and findings. In the time we have left, I feel that as long as we maintain our teamwork and collaboration, we will be able to achieve our goals and help connect GeoTools to the Ingres database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoxiao&amp;#039;s Midway Update-Ingres</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/02/xiaoxiaos-midway-update-ingres/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 21:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/02/xiaoxiaos-midway-update-ingres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My overall progress is a bit slower than I expected, because environment setup took me too long in early February. But I have started implementing actual code and current progress seems good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main difficulty I have had so far is setting up development and testing environment. A large scale open source project such as geotools requires me to install and configure a lot of programs before development starts. Therefore, this setup progress is time-consuming and requires attention to detail.  I set one argument in a single program&amp;#8217;s configuration to a wrong value, and the whole project wouldn&amp;#8217;t build. This mistake wasn&amp;#8217;t discovered until after I spend 5 days double checking all settings and with Lim&amp;#8217;s help. Moreover, a Ubuntu crash forced me to reinstall the system and to started all over again. However, I find this (rather painful) process valuable and rewarding, since this is the first time I need to do so many configurations at the same time(linux, java, eclipse, mvn, geotool, geoserver, openvpn) to make software work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reading overhead is also much more than the actually development. I have to spend at least 3 hours per week to read online documentations, mailing lists, and book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the overhead in setting up environment and reading greatly helps us to understand what we need to write. Writing code is really the last and easiest thing to do if you can understand the problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony&amp;#039;s Midway Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/anthonys-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 06:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/anthonys-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ingres support for Geotools has been progressing well. However, although we are already half way thru the term, we still have quite a ways to go, so we are beginning to pick up the pace a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments and Observations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; It seems like there is a lot of overhead and learning compared to the actually size of the code being developed. This has been a great learning opportunity, although it seems like given the learning curve, it would have been more effective if this project was longer than just one term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; There was good communication within our team. This has been very important, as it has kept everyone up to date, motivated, and made sure that we were all on the right track. Weekly teleconference meetings have been very effective and I don&amp;#8217;t feel that we have suffered from not being able to meet face to face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; I came in with less experience with actually software development experience than other team members, so I spent a lot of my time bringing my skills up to speed (i.e. linux, svn, maven, etc). Again, this was a good learning opportunity for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Lots of time spent writing status updates, reading mailing lists, reading emails, etc. This was a little surprising for me, but I soon realized how essential and beneficial communication and staying organized is. I particularly benefited from the knowledge of my teammates and mailing list participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Lots of time spent installing and configuring supporting software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Our mentor, Andrew, has been very helpful in providing us with any required support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; The average time put in per week was more than I had expected. After the first two weeks I realized I needed to put in at least 10 hrs per week to keep up. This has been very rewarding though, so no complaints!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are some of my status updates for the past few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week of January 31st&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve done this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; followed Lim&amp;#8217;s instructions to set up debugging for GeoServer in Eclipse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; took a detailed look at the test classes proposed by Henry. I agree with his proposed action items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; need to confirm whether skipColumnTest is necessary, my initial thought would be that it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; spent a few hours trying without success to get the opengeo workshop to work with regards to writing data.. currently waiting for some help from geoserver mailing list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; having some problems with moving a school and then saving&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;error msg: 06 Feb 15:31:41 ERROR [geoserver.ows] &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;org.geoserver.wfs.WFSException: Could not locate FeatureStore for &amp;#8216;schools&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week of February 7th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve done this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; got OpenLayers to write to postgis via Geoserver (using example code from opengeo workshop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;issue was that table in query did not specify a workspace, and no default workspace was set. Upgraded to GeoServer 2.0.1 to be able to set appropriate default workspace&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; mailed copyright form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; received SVN access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; continued reading GIS pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week of February 14th&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;#8217;ve done this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; import ingres project into eclipse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; read jdbc notes doc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; communicated with henry about test classes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; added 5 test classes&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ingres/Geotools Lim&amp;#039;s Midway Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/ingresgeotools-lims-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 20:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/ingresgeotools-lims-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ingres/Geotools team finally began work on actual implementation of classes and unit tests for the classes in Geotools at this halfway point. I personally feel that we are falling a little bit behind schedule, not beyond managable. We took our time in the initial phase afraid of making mistakes that compromises the quality of the output. The Ingres/Geotools team has have a lot to explore in the geospatial world as a toddler would have the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already defined a very clear goal since the beginning and based on that, we finally setup in &lt;a href=&#34;http://community.ingres.com/wiki/IngresGeoTools&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;our plan&lt;/a&gt;, Looking at the size of the project in the beginning it seems reasonable, even at this point when we have detailed action items, I believe we are on the right track and its possible to see the project through its completion. However measuring against that, implies that we need to catch up on the actual implementation as we have got a lot to grind through. I personally do not think the effort spent in the first half of the term is wasteful, it just means we have a limited time left to execute the plan, a plan now much clearer than it would have been should we not have communicated and spent time understanding the concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are already learning at this point through the challenges and lack of information we have faced, that is how the real industry works, no matter how our courses have been like. We will continue to face these challenges but we learnt to be ready for it, and we could catch up by wasting no time trying and asking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geotools Status Report</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/02/geotools-status-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 16:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/02/geotools-status-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Geotools team had been working on mostly getting oriented to Geospatial concepts, determining action items, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now ready to create a new unsupported jdbc-ingres module into Geotools. In the coming weeks, you will see rapid additions of new code in the Geotools source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;quot;What we learnt&amp;quot; &#43; &amp;quot;Where we&amp;#039;ll go&amp;quot;</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/01/what-we-learnt-where-well-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2010 15:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/01/what-we-learnt-where-well-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The day before the sprint, I knew of nothing about what I should do and what I can do in this project. I woke up at 5 on Friday morning, took a taxi to the bus terminal, got onto Greyhound to Toronto, got lost on our way to Bahen Centre (we were on University and College, 5 minutes away from Bahen, lol)  To my surprise, I arrived, and joined a team of people as lost as I was. We found out throughout the sprint, many differences between universities, the courses, the cultures, etc. But all of us being in our last year, I believe there&amp;#8217;s one thing in common that we&amp;#8217;ve learnt before we get there: Well, no one&amp;#8217;s going to help us if we don&amp;#8217;t start helping ourselves. Before long, the whole team started the sprint ourselves. We asked lots and lots of questions (Thank you very much Andrew for your detailed presentation and all your help even by having to whisper), we read wiki pages, downloaded source code and snorkeled in it. No one sat still waiting for an answer, there was no awkward silent moment as the team of &amp;#8220;professionals&amp;#8221; blended from the very first day and moved forward as one. The three days went by very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We learnt the following during the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; OpenLayers draws map using Web Mapping Service provided by Geoserver, which in turns uses Geotools to obtain GeoSpatial Data from databases. Geotools can currently talk to many databases but not Ingres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; In Geotools there are connectivity code under modules/plugin/jdbc and modules/plugin that uses various jdbc implementations to connect to various databases. There is also a deprecated version of the framework scheduled to be removed soon. Ingres team needs to make a similar jdbc implementation under Geotools to add support for Ingres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Sara and Eva will be working on the Ingres server side to make sure GeoSpatial queries are handled properly, while Anthony, Henry, Xiaoxiao and Lim work on Geotools to add Ingres support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided the following during the sprint:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project lead will communicate with the team and with the community at large to keep everyone informed about the status of the team, and make sure the team is moving in the right direction. Lim will take on this role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high-level view of the project is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Study the code and play with Geotools in action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Design and plan potential changes to Geotools source tree&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Implement the designs and also implement support for GeoSpatial data in Ingres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; Unit test the Ingres connectivity code in Geotools, test GeoSpatial data support in Ingres, and system test Geotools actually using Ingres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now everyone&amp;#8217;s back to where they are from, but technology is constantly connecting us together. We are all a phone call/email/IM message away from each other, and we are preparing for the next get-together online every Monday with more progress to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Sprint Summary</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/01/code-sprint-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 19:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2010/01/code-sprint-summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TODO’s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Get a duplicated copy of GeoTools repository for UCOSP own builds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Install Geoserver. Do preliminary testing with PostgreSQL w/ PostGIS, feeding to GeoServer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Continue studying the code and understand how JDBC works to connect to difference databases in GeoTools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Break down the database connectivity code among developers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Assign the following tasks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o 2 developers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o 1 tester&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o 1 project manager, where half the time is spent on project management, the other half as developer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Contact Frank W for building Ingres on his server and set up username and password for us. We can then SSH into his server if we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Post a sprint summary for Greg to log down our findings the past few days&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; For each of us, log down meeting minutes in our own blog every week for our phone chat with Andrew (?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Design Document&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should contain the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o List of files needed for GeoTools to run with Ingres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o A class diagram for the Ingres design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o A diagram displaying the architecture of our project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;o A test plan that assesses the validity of our code for GeoTools with Ingres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Create a video showing how Geotools works with Ingres&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Methods of Communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Google Wave&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; IRC Channels: #ingres, #geotools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Mailing lists: Geotools-devel, IngresGIS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Conference calling via Asterisk – follow-up with Andrew on instructions to connect&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henry Chow</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/henry-chow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2010 12:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2010/01/henry-chow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;a href=&#34;http://hkchow.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cimg2001-sep1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img title=&#34;CIMG2001-sep&#34; src=&#34;http://hkchow.files.wordpress.com/2010/01/cimg2001-sep1.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;201&#34; height=&#34;170&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Hey all! My name is Henry. I&amp;#8217;m a 4th year computer science student at the University of British Columbia. I am also minoring in Commerce. My interests lies in the e-commerce field, such as creating bank applications and websites. I have a good knowledge in Java, SQL, VBA and HTML. I have worked at MDA, Nokia, Quartz Imaging, and HSBC in my previous co-op job placements. I look forward to meeting all of you!
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anthony McCallum</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/anthony-mccallum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 03:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/anthony-mccallum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/photo-320.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright size-medium wp-image-1783&#34; title=&#34;Photo 320&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/photo-320.jpg?w=300&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hi, I&amp;#8217;m Anthony McCallum.  I&amp;#8217;m in my final year of a computer science degree at the University of British Columbia. My language of choice is JAVA, but I also have experience with a variety of other languages.  I will be working on the Ingres project this coming term.  This will be my first opportunity to work on an open source project, and I am excited for the challenge!  I&amp;#8217;ve previously done internships with RIM in Ottawa as well as a bioninformatics lab in Singapore.  I am also currently working part time for a UBC affiliated lab.  Looking forward to meeting everyone at the code sprint!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheang Lim Goh</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/cheang-lim-goh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 15:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/cheang-lim-goh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/lim.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-1746&#34; title=&#34;lim&#34; src=&#34;http://ucosp.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/lim.jpg?w=126&#34; alt=&#34;lim&#34; width=&#34;126&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi I am Lim, a fourth year Computer Science/Business Option student from the University of Waterloo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be joining the Ingres team next term. My experience lies primarily with C++ but I also speak a little Java and C#. This will be my first time working on a open-source database project, with focus on managing geospatial data, moreover a team as unique as ours! I look forward to working with Prof. Greg and everyone, see you all in January!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoxiao Li</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/xiaoxiao-li/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2009 03:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/bios/2009/12/xiaoxiao-li/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, I am Xiaoxiao Li, a fourth year CS student at University of Waterloo. I will join the Ingres team in the coming term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done my work terms with three different companies. Through these work terms I developed my interest in database-related technology, including hierarchical data, spatial search, non-relational database, and scalable architecture . This project will be my first time participating in open source development. I hope I could do my best to contribute to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sorry I don&amp;#8217;t have a picture at hand. But I look forward to seeing you in Toronto!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screencast of showing building of Geospatial with GEOS as non root user on Linux</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/12/screencast-of-showing-building-of-geospatial-with-geos-as-non-root-user-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2009 04:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/12/screencast-of-showing-building-of-geospatial-with-geos-as-non-root-user-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following tutorial video is done with GEOS 3.2.0, compiled in gcc 4.3 and g++ 4.3 depending on Xerces C headers and libraries 2.8, pam-devel, pax, jam, on a Debian server as a non root user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube=&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7no3_39GNx0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7no3_39GNx0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, please visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i-wa.blogspot.com/2009/12/screencast-showing-building-geos-and.html&#34;&gt;http://i-wa.blogspot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/12/post-mortem-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2009 10:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/12/post-mortem-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I almost feel as if this post should be titled &amp;#8220;Pre Moretm,&amp;#8221; simply because my work on this project is far from over. Admittedly, I have not had a fraction of the time that I thought I would have at the beginning of the semester, leaving me with a laundry list of work that still needs to be done on Ingres. For the entirety of this semester, it never ceased to amaze me how even though my class work load (projects, assignments, exams, etc.) kept on getting bigger and busier, but the Ingres team just kept plugging on. I suppose that&amp;#8217;s the nature of any large-scale open source project that&amp;#8217;s still &amp;#8220;alive&amp;#8221; and well, if you stop for even one second, it&amp;#8217;s going to keep moving and leave you in it&amp;#8217;s dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several factors that contributed to my falling behind on my Ingres course work, but I believe the most significant one to be my inability to properly manage deadlines on a large scale. I&amp;#8217;ve found that when it comes to internal project deadlines, I&amp;#8217;m usually able to meet them with something close to or exceeding the assignment specifications. On the other hand, managing multiple internal deadlines across multiple projects has become quite difficult for me. As a team manager for a group project in my software engineering class, I usually have some sort of deadline to meet every 3 to 4 days. On top of that, weekly assignments and bi-weekly projects from my media processing class make my academic schedule even more complicated. Finally, if you mix in my exams in for all four of my local classes, you&amp;#8217;ll have a schedule that certainly does not lend itself well to yet another work load with semi-frequent deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, here are the best and the worst of the experiences that I&amp;#8217;ve had while working on UCOSP project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro:&lt;/strong&gt; I think that the best thing I&amp;#8217;ll take away from this semester would have to be the experience of working on a distributed team with such a fine collection of students. Despite the difficult that I&amp;#8217;ve had keeping up with Ingres on top of my already busy academic schedule, they seem to be managing their time quite well. Hopefully I can learn something from them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Con:&lt;/strong&gt; I believe that one of the larger con&amp;#8217;s that I&amp;#8217;ve experienced during UCOSP was having to use a blog to create status reports. Some students (such as myself) do not write or follow blogs, which I believe negatively impacted the quality and frequency of my status reports. Rather than posting to a blog, which to me felt like an improper use of time, I believe that more frequent team meetings and teleconferences would produce better work out of all team members. Frequent meeting would keep each team member accountable for their own work, and teleconferences would allow members to interact on a much more personal level than that of a blog. Rather than turning the students participating in UCOSP into yet another voice on the internet with something to say, I believe that it would be more beneficial to turn them into another user with something to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;thumbs up: Getting the opportunity to work with so many interacting technologies was a challenge. It forced me to take care with the documentation I have been preparing, and given me some inspiration as to ways that documentation could be organized better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thumbs down: Meetings were often canceled and it was hard to set attainable personal goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I feel the course has been helpful. It was extremely frustrating at times because I felt like I was spending so much time dealing with installation problems and not always knowing what work was necessary to get to the next step. That frustration, I think, was key to learning how to work with multiple open source communities where everyone is setting their own deadlines and is dealing with other time constraints as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 17:31:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good: I had a real good experience. It was a challenge still because we have not finished yet, but we learned how to solve problems that can apply to real world challenges in the computer science field. Talking with the Ingres community via email and IRC channel was real helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad: We should communicate more often via UCOSP. We all work in separate ways with the Ingress community. We should do a written report every week to reinforce the meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>