<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eclipse4edu on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/eclipse4edu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eclipse4edu on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 19:50:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/eclipse4edu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 of the Sprint</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2010/01/day-3-of-the-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 19:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2010/01/day-3-of-the-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend, we focused on finding the main aspects of the program that we think need working on and deciding where to go with each one.  Specifically, there was the simplification of toolbars and menus to cater to beginner programmers, comparing the Java versus Scheme parts of the project and approaching the open bugs that have already been identified.  Also we experimented with the program from a first year student standpoint to determine what is and isn&amp;#8217;t necessary and went from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, Dwight Deugo met with us and discussed the structure and aims of the project, a bit of the history of Eclipse, plus where we could go with it over the next few months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found and reported some bugs/tasks that are possibilities to look into this semester, as well as spent a lot of time looking through the code to become more familiar with the extensive framework of Eclipse.  This was a major task but will make things easier in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We intend to have weekly meetings on Fridays at 2:00 Eastern Time, using Skype as our main communication method.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>