<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mercurial on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/mercurial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mercurial on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 03:39:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/mercurial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mercurial Status Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/03/mercurial-status-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2010 03:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/03/mercurial-status-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week in mercurial we all continued to make progress on our various  bfiles features.  I will let our  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ucosp.fogbugz.com/default.asp?W1&#34;&gt;This week in mercurial we all continued to make progress on our various  bfiles features.  I will let our&lt;/a&gt; speak for itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our meeting we discussed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How Anton, Wendy and I will release  auto* features to the mailing list:  In three seperate patches, after we have verified that they work together and don&amp;#8217;t explode too badly when merged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alex discussed some of the details of  how to implement hg serve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul discussed how to approach bfilesify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benjamin will be on vacation next week, so we won&amp;#8217;t have a meet, but Benjamin expects to return to great progress on bfiles 🙂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transcript  of the meeting can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://ucosp.fogbugz.com/default.asp?W40&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tessa&amp;#039;s Midway Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/tessas-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2010/02/tessas-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In General, I feel that I started the term out well, but I am presently falling behind my expectations, the “midterm slump” as Benjamin calls it. Within the first few weeks of the term had I submitted my bug fix to the Mercurial mailing list. I hoped that each week I would have completed some tangible amount of coding, whether it be implementing a small bit of functionality or fixing a bug in last week’s work. This expectation arose from the fact that I feel I should have something to show for my efforts at each weekly status meeting. Since we started working on the bfiles extension, however, I find that all I have done is some discussion and reading through the existing code. These are important activities, but I have gone three weeks without any code written for bfiles, so I need to get down to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One challenge for me for the remainder of the term is finding the middle ground between coding without thinking and being paralyzed by indecision. The freedom UCOSP provides form rigid assignment definitions comes with the obligation to make some design decisions . As the existentialist say, we are doomed to choose. My personal tendency towards indecision and the difficulties coming to a consensus as a group are obstacles that this project will allow me to confront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I think I am learning the most about, or at least have been exposed to more than I have previously, is communicating with other developers online. Our team has been using IRC and email to communicate between ourselves . We have had some interesting discussions with more experienced Mercurial developer on the the Mercurial-devel mailing Benjamin has been very helpful with giving tips and answering questions about mailing list etiquette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I have a positive outlook for our progress over the rest of the term. I feel that there are some challenges ahead, but we are certainly up to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Push: Mercurial</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/mercurial/2010/01/first-push-mercurial-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2010 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/mercurial/2010/01/first-push-mercurial-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During this Code Sprint we focused on a few improvements to Mercurial that make it easier and safer to use. Each of the tasks we worked on was scoped such that only one developer was needed, but this gave everyone a chance to dive head-first into the Mercurial codebase at their own pace. For some (myself included) this is also the first serious project in Python, and these two days were a great opportunity to ask lots of questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re well on our way implementing support for using git sub-repositories, interactively editing Mercurial&amp;#8217;s config files (&lt;code&gt;.hgrc&lt;/code&gt;), cache annotations, auto-merging &lt;code&gt;.hgtags&lt;/code&gt;, matching wildcards when converting from a different source-control system to Mercurial, and preventing users from using files whose names differ only in case (i.e. &lt;code&gt;filename&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;FileName&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve also discussed the harder problems we&amp;#8217;re attempting over the next few months, namely fixing the way Mercurial handles history for large file renames, improving the way very large files are being stored, and improving &lt;code&gt;hg serve&lt;/code&gt; output. And we&amp;#8217;re sure there will be plenty more to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to take a look at what&amp;#8217;s going on in our world, please check out the  &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.fogbugz.com&#34; title=&#34;UCOSP FogBugz&#34;&gt;UCOSP FogBugz&lt;/a&gt; install and log in with &lt;code&gt;Guest/anonymous&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>