<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Midway on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/midway/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Midway on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 03:25:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/midway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Chris Van &amp;#8211; Midway Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/03/chris-van-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 03:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/03/chris-van-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Working on Basie has been a blast! And the team, they&amp;#8217;re really a first-class bunch. Well, to quote Greg, Basie has seen a &amp;ldquo;flurry of activity&amp;rdquo; in the recent weeks as we prepared to debut Basie 0.6. We have all done tremendous work fixing many outstanding bugs, discovering new issues and solutions, refactoring a bunch of code, and redesigning the interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These past few months I&amp;#8217;ve worked mostly on fixing old issues and redesigning the Dashboard. Now that we&amp;#8217;ve pushed Basie 0.6 out the door, I&amp;#8217;ve begun working on a migration tool to import data from Trac. And I&amp;#8217;d say I am very much on track. 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m glad I discovered how amazingly useful a tool like ReviewBoard can be. And status reports and weekly IRC meetings have certainly been helpful to see where we all stand, where our priorities should be, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we&amp;#8217;re only halfway through the term, I&amp;#8217;m excited to see all the new additions come together soon for our 0.7 release.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So, we still have some time to come up with something working, right?</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/02/so-we-still-have-some-time-to-come-up-with-something-working-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 19:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2010/02/so-we-still-have-some-time-to-come-up-with-something-working-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are half-way through the term and I am enjoying working on Basie a lot. I think in our team we didn&amp;#8217;t have much time to play around and get used to the project because 0.6 was planned soon. This gave a very energetic push in the beginning of the year, and 0.7 is something that pushes me to try my best and do work in time now, when 0.6 is out. It&amp;#8217;s very convenient when you know your tasks and your due dates :]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent most of my time before 0.6 fixing lots and lots of issues we had with Basie to make it stable before the release. That helped me to learn the internals of the project faster while also doing useful work. I wrote and iterated over the first several revisions of the tool for Basie that will help to populate a fresh install with random data for demo and testing purposes. My current work includes tackling some core features of Basie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel very much on track personally, mostly by looking at my past experiences with project courses and the general dynamics of my team: everyone is still (midterm time!) very much pokable by email, status reports list real (as oppose to fictitious) items, and reviews on the review board happen regularly 🙂&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eva&amp;#039;s midway update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/status/2010/02/evas-midway-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 03:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/status/2010/02/evas-midway-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my second semester joining the UCOSP with Ingres. From the lessons that I have learnt last term, I have planned my schedule out at the start from reading off the requirements of this semester and so far I am sticking to it quite well. I have completed half of the required patches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only I found myself matured in how to co-operate with people working oversea, but also in self-monitoring. At this point, I am quite accurate about the estimate that I am making to myself, especially on my speed of work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>