<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post Mortem on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/post-mortem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post Mortem on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 19:33:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/post-mortem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid FAIL</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/12/how-to-avoid-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 19:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/12/how-to-avoid-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spurred by some of the MSU students&amp;#8217; experiences this term, here are some thoughts on how to manage expectations on team projects: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ivory.idyll.org/blog/dec-09/aggressive-competence.html&#34; target=&#34;_self&#34;&gt;be aggressively competent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Thumb Up, One Thumb Down</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/12/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 14:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/12/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thumbs up: They way the students on the project came together and worked as a team, holding IRC meetings, sharing emails and conference calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thumbs down: The project started off slower than expected, in part to the existing infrastructure and rules of interaction with Eclipse projects and with me becoming familiar with supervising such a unique student course experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what worked and what needs work</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/elmcity/2009/12/what-worked-and-what-needs-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 12:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/elmcity/2009/12/what-worked-and-what-needs-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First off, thank you to Greg and all the profs and TAs that made this project course possible.  It was definitely a unique and invaluable experience that I believe all students should consider in their undergraduate years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working full-time as a programmer for 3 years now and I wish I had taken this course during my undergrad as this course is extremely applicable to real life work practices.  It teaches you about the importance of communication and coordination with teams across the world with respect to solving a problem.  This is a very common scenario in the workplace, whether it be communication, design,  integrating code, code reviews, etc&amp;#8230;and this course helps set you in that mindset and find ways to work with it.  Overcoming obstacles like timezone differences can be difficult but not impossible.  With good planning and communication, teams can work very well together and produce results.  This course definitely puts you in that perspective and forces you to realize the importance of planning and communication.  Having this experience before setting out full-time as a programmer or any profession in fact gives you a great additional skill set!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What needs work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, working &amp;#8216;virtually&amp;#8217; with teammates really posed a challenge with respect to communication.  I know this is something many teams posted about but I&amp;#8217;m going to emphasize on the planning aspect of communication.  A good plan could lead to a good design which in turn could lead to good direction.  The code sprint was a great chance for teams to spend the time planning and designing their systems but after that, it was difficult to do any.  As a result, no one actually &amp;#8216;fully&amp;#8217; understood the entire system.  It&amp;#8217;s difficult to design out the whole system at first and many requirements can change along the way.  I think implementing an iterative design and development process could have worked here.  Rather than looking at milestones, look at perhaps shorter two week sprints.  Dedicate a couple of days before each two week sprint to plan out what needs to be done in that period, address design issues for only those tasks and work on those specific items.  After a sprint, address outstanding issues and move on to the next set of tasks needed.  Taking on the system in appropriate chunks not only allows you to focus in on a specific area, but it allows you to understand how one part integrates with the next and realize what works and doesn&amp;#8217;t work with the design early on.  It also gives you more direction because you are not overwhelmed with the big picture.  Communication with respect to these smaller iterative periods could be improved as well since everyone understands what is going on and what needs to be done in that two week cycle.  Perhaps this is something that could be considered within teams to help the struggle of meeting deadlines, communication and direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for the great experience everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Positive, One Negative</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/robocup/2009/12/one-positive-one-negative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/robocup/2009/12/one-positive-one-negative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Positive: Finally, I can experience working on a real, fully distributed team. Also, I learn a lot of technical stuff from this course. From programming in python to machine learning algorithms. I am also grateful to learn from my colleagues as this is more practical than learning from textbooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negative: I couldn&amp;#8217;t contribute to the team as much as I want to. There are various reasons for this but most notably is due to the complexity and difficulty of the project. As time goes by, I discover more stuff that can&amp;#8217;t be done than stuff that can be done. There is certainly a way to fix it but given the fact that we are expected to work ~10 hours per week, we would end up fixing stuff rather than achieving our goals. Thus, sometimes hacking is the most appropriate (but not the best) way to do it. If I would do it again in the future, it would be very nice to have someone that is knowledgeable to tell us what could possibly be done by 50 hours of work per week over four months. Unfortunately, it is very hard to find such person in any project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly (Minus the Ugly)</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-minus-the-ugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 16:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-minus-the-ugly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Good:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to learn how people are using tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://friendfeed.com/&#34;&gt;FriendFeed&lt;/a&gt; to interact directly with their end-users. I know there are a lot of solutions to that specific problem, but my experience with large scale work in the past had only ever been internal projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lack of direction. I understand that this wasn&amp;#8217;t really a problem for a lot of the projects, but I feel that ours suffered it in spades. We didn&amp;#8217;t have a shareholder who was really hands-on and invested in what we were doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One up, one down</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-up-one-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 05:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-up-one-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whups, it appears I missed the original email on doing this writing assignment&amp;#8211;apologies for it being a bit late!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll start with my thoughts on the positives for this course first.  I really feel I&amp;#8217;ve learned a great deal about working with a distance group on a software project&amp;#8211;something normal CS coursework doesn&amp;#8217;t really prepare one for (and even precious little time is spent in the courses I&amp;#8217;ve taken on working with more or less random groups as well).  There are definite difficulties in the process, but it&amp;#8217;s been a great experience learning these things firsthand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the negative.  Looking at some of the other posts, I think I would be redundant if I simply mentioned the lack of structure in the course, so I would like to point out at least one thing specifically&amp;#8211;I&amp;#8217;m going to pick on the grading schemes here (I was already thinking about writing this up before I saw Eric&amp;#8217;s post just below mine&amp;#8211;I guess this is ending up being a long extension on one of the subjects to touched on).  It&amp;#8217;s an interesting idea to have the students decide how their own projects will be graded, but I don&amp;#8217;t think it worked out very well this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really feel there needs to be a more definite overall grading scheme.  I went through all my emails from UCOSP going back to the beginning of the term, and didn&amp;#8217;t see anything with any sort of set grading scheme.  Through the semester we&amp;#8217;ve been asked to do various things (several writing assignments, project presentation video, etc), but these pop up more or less at random, and other than being told basically that &amp;#8220;it will affect my grade&amp;#8221;, I have no idea how they will affect my grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If at the beginning of the term we could see something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Initial writing assignment: X% of final grade&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project status updates: Y% of final grade&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final project video: Z% of final grade&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Along with item due dates*, I feel that would be immensely helpful.  The specifics of the items don&amp;#8217;t have to be filled out at that point, but would make sure students knew ahead of time when something was going to be due, and around when to check back for more information.  For example, I somehow missed Greg&amp;#8217;s first email about this writing assignment&amp;#8211;but thought nothing of it, because I guess I didn&amp;#8217;t remember seeing the initial email, and I didn&amp;#8217;t know to expect one&amp;#8211;so the current terrible signal-to-noise ratio of my inbox took over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then for some set percent of the overall final grade, students could do what we did this term and pick how their final deliverable would be graded at the end of the term.  However, that would not be their *entire* grading scheme, but section of a more structured grading chart.  This would allow not only for the projects to be graded more simply, but would allow students to get a better feel as to how they are progressing throughout the course, and have a better idea on how to schedule their time through the term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I do think that more structured grading would be a great thing for this course, what students could get out of it, and positively impact the final products as a result.  I like the ideas here &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.wordpress.com/2009/11/16/some-ideas-for-next-term/&#34;&gt;http://ucosp.wordpress.com/2009/11/16/some-ideas-for-next-term/&lt;/a&gt; as a start, but to implement those ideas, we&amp;#8217;re also going to need structured grading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a great experience overall though!  I know this post is a little long, so I hope it all made sense&amp;#8211;feel free to comment if anyone wants me to make any part of my long rambling here more clear / want me to explain anything better 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and it&amp;#8217;s been great working with everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>for what it&amp;#039;s worth: my two cents</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/for-what-its-worth-my-two-cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 06:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/for-what-its-worth-my-two-cents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The good cent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would definitely say that the best part of my UCOSP experience has been my project &amp;#8220;mentor&amp;#8221;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.latte.ca/blake&#34;&gt;Blake Winton&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;#8217;m not sure how he put up with my incessant IRC messages at all times of the day Sunday through Saturday.  I learned a lot about &lt;a href=&#34;http://mercurial.selenic.com/&#34;&gt;Mercurial&lt;/a&gt; and distributed version control from him, and he was always so chill that I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but want to work on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/Thunderbird/ISPDB&#34;&gt;ISPDB&lt;/a&gt;.  It&amp;#8217;s too bad he&amp;#8217;s not grading me for the course, otherwise this might be a nice little push towards a good grade 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The bad cent:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the structure.  I didn&amp;#8217;t bother reading all of the other post mortems so I hope that I&amp;#8217;m not repeating anyone here&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long version:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The structure of the course made it hard to give it priority equal to my other courses.  I know that I still put in a good amount of work, but I would have liked to put in more.  I liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://ucosp.wordpress.com/2009/11/16/some-ideas-for-next-term/&#34;&gt;the idea that &amp;#8220;Greg&amp;#8221; had&lt;/a&gt; (I know your dirty secret on this one Greg, and it&amp;#8217;s safe with me 🙂 ),  but I think it still needs more structure.  If the 3rd suggestion had a percentage of the total grade (like 30%) where you either got your weekly milestone done (or a good blog post about what you came up against that kept you from completion) or you lost a percentage of your total grade.  As it stands now, it&amp;#8217;s hard to see the real repercussions of missing milestones since they don&amp;#8217;t have a direct, quantifiable effect on your grade.  I could go on about this one, but unless someone comments with questions I&amp;#8217;m going to lay this to rest&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 04:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thumbs up:&lt;/strong&gt; first of all, know a lot of new friends:) this is most valuable. Second, learn how to cooperation with each other, even we are far away from each other. We use IRC to hold and log team meeting, wiki page to schedule and record our process, bugzilla to keep track of everything. Those tools contribute a lot to the final success of the project. For the technical aspect, I learn the new language flex and use it to create the UI and animation for the front end.  It&amp;#8217;s an amazing tools for data representations and I am so glad that I can apply it to the real work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thumbs down:&lt;/strong&gt; The only problem that I can see is that the open source projects are lack of documentation. We start with thinking and end with coding. But if we do have documents, for one things, we can realize what we are gonna do much faster. For another, if we create documents while developing, it will be much easier for the fellows to improve our work or continue the unfinished parts. Otherwise, they may have to spend some time to understand our code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I will rank very high for this projects. We can do something which is meaning for lots of people, instead of coding just for assignments. Lots of useful tools are involved and I can improve my working skills through the whole semester. BTW, I really miss the trip for the Toronto and saw the beautiful city.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good, the bad and the Basie</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-basie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 02:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-basie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good:&lt;/strong&gt; I learned a lot about web frameworks (specifically, Django) and jQuery applications from Basie. Without having any web development background, the course allowed me to move at my own pace while still absorbing lots of information that I will likely retain for future employment opportunities. Not only that, but the reference gained by doing such a project is certainly one of the best ways to get your foot in the door (here&amp;#8217;s looking at you, Greg ;)).  Basie was my first taste of the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bad:&lt;/strong&gt; Code reviews were daunting since team members were focused on very particular aspects of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judging by factors that extend beyond the mere comparative lengths of the two preceding paragraphs, the good most certainly outweighs the bad. Having a web development course under my belt, I&amp;#8217;ve decided to continue experimenting with CSC49X and am now on board for a project with a much different flavour: image recognition. I&amp;#8217;m very excited how far-reaching and open-ended these projects can be and hope that more students, as I did, will have the opportunity to apply their knowledge to something meaningful in the coming terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;thumbs up: Getting the opportunity to work with so many interacting technologies was a challenge. It forced me to take care with the documentation I have been preparing, and given me some inspiration as to ways that documentation could be organized better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thumbs down: Meetings were often canceled and it was hard to set attainable personal goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I feel the course has been helpful. It was extremely frustrating at times because I felt like I was spending so much time dealing with installation problems and not always knowing what work was necessary to get to the next step. That frustration, I think, was key to learning how to work with multiple open source communities where everyone is setting their own deadlines and is dealing with other time constraints as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and Down</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/up-and-down-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/up-and-down-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Up: One of the best parts for me was learning what a great thing constructive criticism is. I practically look forward to a denied patch because of the amount of feedback and the opportunity for improvement. This was refreshing after just getting a discouragingly low mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down: The delay of email sometimes causes all progress to halt because I just didn&amp;#8217;t know how to proceed. This would cause breaks and dry spells, something I found tough to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another two thumbs</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/another-two-thumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 17:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/another-two-thumbs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thumbs Up: Getting to work on an exploratory project, and seeing what it ended up becoming. WikiDev didn&amp;#8217;t have as defined a goal at the start as most projects, but instead a framework to build on and ideas for where we could take things. After that, it was up to everyone to discuss every week and see where we wanted to go next. This was very enlightening and I enjoyed seeing how the project evolved as pieces were completed and we could see what our ideas were shaping up to look like. I am used to working on projects where the plan is fairly complete and spec&amp;#8217;d out before any code is written, so this made for an interesting change of pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thumb Down: Working on an exploratory project, especially for motivation and getting invested. The flip side of the coin is that with a less defined idea and direction, it was sometimes hard to see where each piece would fit into the whole. I always knew what I was working on at any given time, without knowing what was coming next or why it was important, I often had a nagging feeling that what I was working on would end up ignored and unused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was a great experience. The code sprint in Toronto was awesome, it was good to build real things in school for a change, and by the efforts of everyone involved it felt like much more than a simple course. I&amp;#8217;d heartily recommend it for anyone else who gets the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And Another Post Mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/and-another-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 11:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/and-another-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apart from the fact that it&amp;#8217;s great to work on a real project. I believe it was invaluable to meet the programmer behind the name at the start of semester. It gave us the chance to not only meet, but perform a little team building as well rather than just a name somewhere in cyberspace. I think that working in a distributed team like this gave us all an experience that we might not get from some IT companies. I&amp;#8217;m really glad that I had the chance to be apart of this course. If we&amp;#8217;ve learned nothing, the very least we can take away from this project is how to deal with a distributed team in the future. But from the sounds of previous posts, we all have something or another that we can take away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Basie, we made it a standard to review code before its submitted. This is not a bad idea, but I decided to split my work into many reviews that took weeks finish. This wasn&amp;#8217;t because the reviews were long, but because as the semester progressed, student reviewers became busy. It became a little difficult to keep things separate when each progressive feature built on top of the previous.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem (ie. &#43;&#43;&amp;amp;death)</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-ie-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 08:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-ie-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Good: I, for one, really loved the grad school talk, I think that it was very insightful and I&amp;#8217;m really glad that we got the opportunity to attend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bad: Can&amp;#8217;t do pair programming when team members are 500km away 🙁 This might be a personal preference but I&amp;#8217;m a huge fan of pair programming, I find development a lot smoother and it&amp;#8217;s also easy to stay motivated and on track. I&amp;#8217;m sure this won&amp;#8217;t be the last time I work in a team setting like this, so I guess all in all it&amp;#8217;s a good experience to go through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through;&#34;&gt;The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:line-through;&#34;&gt;Ugly:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 06:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thumbs up: Mozilla&amp;#8217;s strict coding standards and having to submit patches and get our code reviewed was very beneficial. It forces you to pay attention to details and you learn a lot more compared to projects that you hack together last minute and hand in whatever works 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thumbs down: The tasks our team worked on were pretty individual and so there wasn&amp;#8217;t much collaboration between us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>