<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ispdb on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/tags/ispdb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ispdb on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 20:22:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/tags/ispdb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First Patch Ever.</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/10/first-patch-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 20:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/10/first-patch-ever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First Patch Ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my pending patch has been checked into the source tree, I will become a member of the open source community. It doesn&amp;#8217;t look like much but it does fix a problem. I take heart from Richard Feynman who said, &amp;#8221; No problem is too small or too trivial if we can really do something about it.&amp;#8221;.  Here is a few things I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Svn needs a better way to manage patches because pending ones causes a mess. To keep from mangling my patch, I ended up having to checkout another copy to code with. If anyone has a better solution please tell me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stand on other people&amp;#8217;s shoulders. We borrowed a custom test runner to integrate the nose test framework into django during the code sprint (Thanks Jeff!). Then we discovered that he maintains a version of it on github so now we point to the source and save ourselves maintence/installation issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;People on IRC are really nice. I needed help with my patch so I hopped on IRC (mozilla/education). It was nice to have someone who knew a lot about coding and ISPDB (David Ascher) take the time to thoroughly discuss the issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>