<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post Mortem on UCOSP</title>
    <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/tags/post-mortem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post Mortem on UCOSP</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 19:33:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/tags/post-mortem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid FAIL</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/12/how-to-avoid-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 19:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/12/how-to-avoid-fail/</guid>
      <description>Spurred by some of the MSU students&amp;#8217; experiences this term, here are some thoughts on how to manage expectations on team projects: be aggressively competent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Thumb Up, One Thumb Down</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/12/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 14:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/12/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down-2/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: They way the students on the project came together and worked as a team, holding IRC meetings, sharing emails and conference calls.
Thumbs down: The project started off slower than expected, in part to the existing infrastructure and rules of interaction with Eclipse projects and with me becoming familiar with supervising such a unique student course experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what worked and what needs work</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/elmcity/2009/12/what-worked-and-what-needs-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 12:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/elmcity/2009/12/what-worked-and-what-needs-work/</guid>
      <description>First off, thank you to Greg and all the profs and TAs that made this project course possible. It was definitely a unique and invaluable experience that I believe all students should consider in their undergraduate years.
What worked:
I&amp;#8217;ve been working full-time as a programmer for 3 years now and I wish I had taken this course during my undergrad as this course is extremely applicable to real life work practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Positive, One Negative</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/robocup/2009/12/one-positive-one-negative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 21:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/robocup/2009/12/one-positive-one-negative/</guid>
      <description>Positive: Finally, I can experience working on a real, fully distributed team. Also, I learn a lot of technical stuff from this course. From programming in python to machine learning algorithms. I am also grateful to learn from my colleagues as this is more practical than learning from textbooks.
Negative: I couldn&amp;#8217;t contribute to the team as much as I want to. There are various reasons for this but most notably is due to the complexity and difficulty of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly (Minus the Ugly)</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-minus-the-ugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 16:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly-minus-the-ugly/</guid>
      <description>The Good:
It was nice to learn how people are using tools like FriendFeed to interact directly with their end-users. I know there are a lot of solutions to that specific problem, but my experience with large scale work in the past had only ever been internal projects.
The Bad:
Lack of direction. I understand that this wasn&amp;#8217;t really a problem for a lot of the projects, but I feel that ours suffered it in spades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One up, one down</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-up-one-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2009 05:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-up-one-down/</guid>
      <description>Whups, it appears I missed the original email on doing this writing assignment&amp;#8211;apologies for it being a bit late!
I&amp;#8217;ll start with my thoughts on the positives for this course first. I really feel I&amp;#8217;ve learned a great deal about working with a distance group on a software project&amp;#8211;something normal CS coursework doesn&amp;#8217;t really prepare one for (and even precious little time is spent in the courses I&amp;#8217;ve taken on working with more or less random groups as well).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>for what it&amp;#039;s worth: my two cents</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/for-what-its-worth-my-two-cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 06:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/for-what-its-worth-my-two-cents/</guid>
      <description>The good cent:
I would definitely say that the best part of my UCOSP experience has been my project &amp;#8220;mentor&amp;#8221;, Blake Winton. I&amp;#8217;m not sure how he put up with my incessant IRC messages at all times of the day Sunday through Saturday. I learned a lot about Mercurial and distributed version control from him, and he was always so chill that I couldn&amp;#8217;t help but want to work on the ISPDB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 04:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-7/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: first of all, know a lot of new friends:) this is most valuable. Second, learn how to cooperation with each other, even we are far away from each other. We use IRC to hold and log team meeting, wiki page to schedule and record our process, bugzilla to keep track of everything. Those tools contribute a lot to the final success of the project. For the technical aspect, I learn the new language flex and use it to create the UI and animation for the front end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good, the bad and the Basie</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-basie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 02:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/the-good-the-bad-and-the-basie/</guid>
      <description>The Good: I learned a lot about web frameworks (specifically, Django) and jQuery applications from Basie. Without having any web development background, the course allowed me to move at my own pace while still absorbing lots of information that I will likely retain for future employment opportunities. Not only that, but the reference gained by doing such a project is certainly one of the best ways to get your foot in the door (here&amp;#8217;s looking at you, Greg ;)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/ingres/2009/11/post-mortem-6/</guid>
      <description>thumbs up: Getting the opportunity to work with so many interacting technologies was a challenge. It forced me to take care with the documentation I have been preparing, and given me some inspiration as to ways that documentation could be organized better.
thumbs down: Meetings were often canceled and it was hard to set attainable personal goals.
All in all, I feel the course has been helpful. It was extremely frustrating at times because I felt like I was spending so much time dealing with installation problems and not always knowing what work was necessary to get to the next step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Up and Down</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/up-and-down-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 19:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/up-and-down-2/</guid>
      <description>Up: One of the best parts for me was learning what a great thing constructive criticism is. I practically look forward to a denied patch because of the amount of feedback and the opportunity for improvement. This was refreshing after just getting a discouragingly low mark.
Down: The delay of email sometimes causes all progress to halt because I just didn&amp;#8217;t know how to proceed. This would cause breaks and dry spells, something I found tough to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another two thumbs</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/another-two-thumbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 17:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/another-two-thumbs/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs Up: Getting to work on an exploratory project, and seeing what it ended up becoming. WikiDev didn&amp;#8217;t have as defined a goal at the start as most projects, but instead a framework to build on and ideas for where we could take things. After that, it was up to everyone to discuss every week and see where we wanted to go next. This was very enlightening and I enjoyed seeing how the project evolved as pieces were completed and we could see what our ideas were shaping up to look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And Another Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/and-another-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 11:38:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/and-another-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>Apart from the fact that it&amp;#8217;s great to work on a real project. I believe it was invaluable to meet the programmer behind the name at the start of semester. It gave us the chance to not only meet, but perform a little team building as well rather than just a name somewhere in cyberspace. I think that working in a distributed team like this gave us all an experience that we might not get from some IT companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem (ie. &#43;&#43;&amp;amp;death)</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-ie-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 08:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-ie-death/</guid>
      <description>The Good: I, for one, really loved the grad school talk, I think that it was very insightful and I&amp;#8217;m really glad that we got the opportunity to attend it.
The Bad: Can&amp;#8217;t do pair programming when team members are 500km away 🙁 This might be a personal preference but I&amp;#8217;m a huge fan of pair programming, I find development a lot smoother and it&amp;#8217;s also easy to stay motivated and on track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 06:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-4/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: Mozilla&amp;#8217;s strict coding standards and having to submit patches and get our code reviewed was very beneficial. It forces you to pay attention to details and you learn a lot more compared to projects that you hack together last minute and hand in whatever works 🙂
Thumbs down: The tasks our team worked on were pretty individual and so there wasn&amp;#8217;t much collaboration between us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem a.k.a. cacoethes scribendi ;)</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-a-k-a-cacoethes-scribendi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 02:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-a-k-a-cacoethes-scribendi/</guid>
      <description>[disclaimer: my own opinion, others might not think the same]
The good: the course itself, was a great experience. I think the most valuable thing is that it made me see the challenges software teams face in the real world and why those challenges can&amp;#8217;t be resolved easily sometimes. In addition, I got a chance to work on a great project, and this is the reason I took this course in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#43;1, -1</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/11/1-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2009 05:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/11/1-1/</guid>
      <description>+1: Collaboration. When the team first started on the project we each worked on bugs that were, for the most part, independent of each other. At around the mid-point of the term, we decided to collaborate more and work on smaller features of a bigger part. This way we were all working toward a common goal. I think we all enjoyed the project much more after we made this decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WikiDev Post-mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/wikidev-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 20:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/wikidev-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>The good: Quite unequivocally, the students. Each member of the team was eager to learn whatever new language we threw at them (PHP, SQL, Flex/MXML/ActionScript), research solutions to overcome problems they encountered, and ask for assistance when needed. With so many variables in this type of distributed course, including the different experiences and skill sets that comes with being from four separate institutions, having a strong team makes quite a difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>post mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/11/post-mortem-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2009 04:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/eclipse4edu/2009/11/post-mortem-3/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up:
 A chance to make a name on a open source project (&amp;#8220;eclipse&amp;#8221;) The formation that Wayne gave us during the code sprint, We would definitly not have acomplished as much without it. Regular project conference call with the team and Dwight. We managed to work as a real team and set-up a svn and irc channel and have 2 irc meeting each week to give each other a status update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did somebody say post-mortem?</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/did-somebody-say-post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 06:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/did-somebody-say-post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>Can&amp;#8217;t believe this is coming to an end already. I&amp;#8217;ve read it before, but let it be the best experience of my undergraduate career too. 🙂
Con : Setting-up
Maybe it&amp;#8217;s just about me (but I don&amp;#8217;t think so), and I know that MarkUs was, by far, not the worst project for that concern, but I didn&amp;#8217;t enjoy the set-up time. One could argue that I never do. One would be right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 05:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem-2/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: Great experience working as part of a geographically dispersed team. In all my co-op terms, I&amp;#8217;ve always worked in an office where I could talk to people face-to-face. Now that my experience has broadened, I expect to be a better team player on future software development projects.
Thumbs down: Sporadic time commitments. As a student with 4 other courses, contributing 8-10 hours a week means working sporadically throughout the week when time permits for 1-3 hour chunks at a time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Post Mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/post-mortem-john-peters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 04:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/basie/2009/11/post-mortem-john-peters/</guid>
      <description>Greg:
You are not allowed to repeat something that someone else has said (which is a good incentive to post early :-).
 Apparently posting within the day isn&amp;#8217;t early enough; there are almost two pages already.
I&amp;#8217;d like to echo what Josh said, both the good and the bad. The best courses in my undergraduate have been the ones where I&amp;#8217;ve done &amp;#8216;real&amp;#8217; work, and the more opportunities I have to do such things the better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some final thoughts&amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/some-final-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 22:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/some-final-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I have really enjoyed working on MarkUs this semester!
One of the things I liked the best was that our TA and one of the students on our team had both already worked on our project before and they knew both MarkUs and Ruby on Rails inside and out. I think that everyone on the team benefited from their past experiences and it was great to be able to get advice from them and ask them questions throughout the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-mortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 20:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/post-mortem/</guid>
      <description>I think that this course was a great way to finish off my undergraduate computer science career. I am working on the MarkUs project.
One of the things that I really like about MarkUs is that we have students working on developing a system that students will use to submit assignments. I really wish that we could use a similar methodology to develop a new course registration system (similar to the functionality that PeopleSoft&amp;#8217;s QUEST currently provides for us) and an online course system (similar to ANGEL or WebCT).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>good and the bad</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/good-and-the-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 19:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/good-and-the-bad/</guid>
      <description>Overall I really enjoyed this course. The one bad thing is that a lot was opened ended. This can be a good thing, however I things like have 2 deliverable dates throughout the semester so we know what we have to accomplish by these dates. Also, making code reviews a requirement and having to turn in a list of goals to accomplish by the end of the code sprint instead of half way through the semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postmortem</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/robocup/2009/11/postmortem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 16:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/robocup/2009/11/postmortem/</guid>
      <description>ThumbUp: Having meetings every week and posting status reports helped keep us on track.
ThumbDown: I think it would be good to have more variety in projects, in particular some that are less development-oriented and involve more research</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[thumbUp, thumbDown].map{&amp;#124;thumb&amp;#124; thumb&#43;&#43;}</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/thumbup-thumbdown-mapthumb-thumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 16:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/thumbup-thumbdown-mapthumb-thumb/</guid>
      <description>ThumbUp: peer reviews. Peer reviews, at least for the Basie team, was certainly a new type of experience in software development. It promoted communication between the team, getting into each other&amp;#8217;s code, writing code that is good enough for others to look at, and then still getting feedback on how to improve it. It creates a better &amp;#8220;team&amp;#8221; feeling, than simply having a group of people commit to the same source code repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thumbUp&#43;&#43;; thumbDown&#43;&#43;;</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/thumbup-thumbdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 15:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/thumbup-thumbdown/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: The code sprint where all students and participating parties gathering face to face provides a precious opportunity for them to know each other, especially on each others&amp;#8217; working style, which helped a lot during the course later on.
Thumbs down: Difference between schools&amp;#8217; expectation from students leads to a significant difference in students&amp;#8217; motivation. If the students are grouped into sub teams working on the same smaller project, we should weight more on continuous communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What went right, wrong this year</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/what-went-right-wrong-this-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 13:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/what-went-right-wrong-this-year/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: Sponsors, I liked the fact that we were able to get further acquainted with large businesses in the computer science field such as Ingres, Tucows, Yahoo, and Rogers Communication. I also agree with Greg&amp;#8217;s point, and it was a good learning experience to work on projects in a different setting and environment.
Thumbs down: Though this may have been expensive, I would&amp;#8217;ve liked to have a UCOSP meeting like the initial sprint at the end of this experience to wrap up the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It was the best of times, it was the worst of times</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/it-was-the-best-of-times-it-was-the-worst-of-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 13:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/wikidev/2009/11/it-was-the-best-of-times-it-was-the-worst-of-times/</guid>
      <description>I am impressed with how much was accomplished in the end. I must say that it is not more than I what was planning/hoping for but at the same time, throughout the course, I had this nagging feeling that things will not come together, and, in the end, we wouldn&amp;#8217;t have anything &amp;#8220;complete&amp;#8221; to show for it. Well we do, and that&amp;#8217;s great!
In spite of notes and discussions and todos and tickets, we still managed to do a few things multiple times (stepping on each other&amp;#8217;s toes).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Really Good Thing Was &amp;#8230;</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-really-good-thing-was/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 13:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/the-really-good-thing-was/</guid>
      <description>Thumbs up: Our great teamwork. Although we are working in a distributed setting, I do find it astonishing how well everything worked out. People are doing a great job in terms of communication.
Thumbs down: Having a pretty tight schedule, I think there was hardly time for one or two developers to go for a spike (i.e. looking into an unknown technological area) and create an example solution to a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two more thumbs for UCOSP</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/two-more-thumbs-for-ucosp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 13:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/two-more-thumbs-for-ucosp/</guid>
      <description>Following up on Greg Wilson&amp;#8217;s post, here&amp;#8217;s another pair of observations about the course; one good and one bad:
Thumbs up: Gaining experience working in a distributed environment is invaluable, but when you add on top of that the fact that we are producing some great open source software, you have a winning combination. Some of us have experience in the industry through co-op and other programs at our universities, but at least for me working on open source was a completely different experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Thumb Up, One Thumb Down</title>
      <link>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 11:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruute0.github.io/hugo-ucosp/2009-2010/uncategorized/2009/11/one-thumb-up-one-thumb-down/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;#8217;re coming up on the end of term, so it&amp;#8217;s time to start thinking about what went right and what went wrong. I&amp;#8217;ve asked the students and mentors to post their ideas here, but to lead off:
Thumbs up: our broad geographic range. I was really pleased to have schools from three oceans (four if you count the Great Lakes) take part.
Thumbs down: most projects weren&amp;#8217;t ready to roll on day one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>