<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncategorized on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://haruute0.github.io/categories/uncategorized/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uncategorized on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://haruute0.github.io/categories/uncategorized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall Projects</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2017/08/22/fall-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2017/08/22/fall-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fall projects are now available.  We are happy to welcome back six projects from recent years.  These include two projects that have been with us since the beginning or nearly the beginning of UCOSP: Reviewboard and Umple.  We are welcoming back Julian and the Formulize project as well as three projects from Mozilla: Firefox development tools, Code Coverage, and Task Cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our new projects include another Firefox Development Tools project on the React debugger, and two new projects with a more analytic focus.  The WALA and Swift project is a collaboration between IBM and the University of Alberta.  The Safe Browsing and Tracker Prevention will involve some data collection and analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I would have a hard time making my choices if I were a student with these options.  Thanks again to the mentors for volunteering their time to work with UCOSP students.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure we will have a great term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2017 Preparation</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2017/08/04/fall-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2017/08/04/fall-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preparations for the next term are well underway.  We are finalizing projects with our project mentors, including some exciting potential new projects.  We haven&amp;rsquo;t updated the project list yet, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code sprint will be at the Mozilla offices in downtown Toronto Sept 22-24. Students will be getting email shortly to start booking flights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter 2017 UCOSP Projects</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/12/05/projects-confirmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/12/05/projects-confirmed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preparations for the winter term are well underway.  We have 34 students signed up and ready to travel to Calgary in January for the code sprint.  Thanks to our enthusiastic and generous mentors, we have 7 projects lined up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to go read the project &lt;a href=&#34;http://haruute0.github.io/projects.html&#34;&gt;descriptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall 2016 UCOSP Projects</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/08/18/projects-confirmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/08/18/projects-confirmed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The open source communities have no shortage of generous people!  We have nine projects ready to go and 28 wonderful mentors to work with students. I&amp;rsquo;d like to welcome back returning mentors from Reviewboard, MarkUs, Umple, Mylyn, and Firefox Code Coverage.  I&amp;rsquo;d especially like to welcome Greg Mierzwinski who is returning as a mentor for Firefox Code Coverage after working on it as a UCOSP student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have four new projects from Mozilla: Firefox 3D Z-index Tool, TaskCluster-Pulse, Pontoon, and FlyWeb.  The projects all look very interesting, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank all the new mentors for joining us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I encourage you to go read the project &lt;a href=&#34;http://haruute0.github.io/projects.html&#34;&gt;descriptions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the Fall term</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/08/04/fall-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/08/04/fall-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Planning is in full swing for the fall term.  Students and faculty are definitely thinking about September.  Looking at our registration form we already have about half the number of students we expect signed up and more are starting to roll in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our fall code sprint will be held at the Mozilla offices in downtown Toronto.  Their community space is a great place to work, and Mike Hoye and his team are excellent hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still finalizing the list of projects.  We have more turnover this year than usual, but the potential new projects looks very interesting.  Longtime projects MarkUs, ReviewBoard, and Umple will be back, and I&amp;rsquo;ll post descriptions of the new projects as soon as they are available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Look and Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/05/30/new-look-and-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/05/30/new-look-and-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;year-in-review:3572a8a49cd37c29e717b45c4ee55b48&#34;&gt;Year in Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another great year with UCOSP, thanks to the generous sponsorship from Google and the support of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cacsaic.org&#34;&gt;CACS/AIC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty-five students attended the September code sprint in Vancouver at the beautiful UBC campus. Our wonderful long term project mentors once again created a great experience for our students.  We welcomed back &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reviewboard.org&#34;&gt;ReviewBoard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeform.ca/en/formulize&#34;&gt;Formulize&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/blackberry/WebWorks-Community-APIs&#34;&gt;BB 10/Phonegap&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://markusproject.org&#34;&gt;MarkUs&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cruise.eecs.uottawa.ca/umple/&#34;&gt;Umple&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were thrilled to welcome back &lt;a href=&#34;http://livingcode.org&#34;&gt;Dethe Elza&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://waterbearlang.com&#34;&gt;Waterbear&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jim-parry-b7179325&#34;&gt;Jim Parry&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeigniter.com&#34;&gt;CodeIgniter&lt;/a&gt;. Both Dethe and Jim live in the Vancouver area which made it possible for them to supervise a project this term.  We also welcomed another local, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sam-davis-4571a825&#34;&gt;Sam Davis&lt;/a&gt; mentoring the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/mylyn/&#34;&gt;Mylyn&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla once again hosted the Toronto code sprint in January in their beautiful community space.  Along with returning projects Reviewboard, MarkUs, Formulize and Umple, we were joined by two Mozilla-based projects: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jupyter.org&#34;&gt;Jupyter Notebook&lt;/a&gt; and Code Coverage.  &lt;a href=&#34;http://mreid-moz.github.io&#34;&gt;Mark Reid&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mozillians.org/en-US/u/jmaher/&#34;&gt;Joel Maher&lt;/a&gt; and their colleagues were naturals at mentoring students, and it was a real pleasure to work them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After several years of working Tim Windsor on the Blackberry/Phonegap projects we were sad not to have him back in January.  We hope that his love of open source software will bring him back on a different project in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflections:3572a8a49cd37c29e717b45c4ee55b48&#34;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a year of changes and time to reflect.  Schools across North America have seen dramatic increases CS program enrolments.  This was evident in the larger numbers of students applying to UCOSP.  For example, at the Univeristy of Toronto we had 75 students apply for 8 UCOSP spots.  There is clearly a demand for the kind of practical learning experience that UCOSP provides.  While we plan to support a slightly larger number of students next year, we are limited by funding and organizational overhead costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the otherhand we also had two schools decide not to send students this year, at least partly because they were not able to find faculty to supervise the students.  Increasing enrolments at our universities means that faculty have less time for the &amp;ldquo;extras&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we have not had difficulty finding interested open source projects.  We saw a higher turnover in projects this year, but we have also had cold call inquiries about how a project might be included in the program.  For the record, we are looking for some new projects for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another change is the makeup of the steering committee.  Michelle is stepping down from the steering committee for a well-earned sabbatical.  Karen Reid will be chairing the committee for the next year.  Rob Walker from the University of Calgary is joining the steering committee.  Meghan Allen, Ted Kirkpatrick, and  Eleni Stroulia continue to serve on the committee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;new-look:3572a8a49cd37c29e717b45c4ee55b48&#34;&gt;New Look&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to move the web site over to github.io, partly to save a bit of money on web hosting, but mostly to make it easier to add posts and maintain the archive of information.  You can still reach us at info@ucosp.ca&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupyter Notebook – UCOSP 2016 – Recap</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/03/24/jupyter-notebook-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/03/24/jupyter-notebook-recap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Adam Wong&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone, now that I am halfway through my UCOSP project, I would like to take some time to reflect and share some of my experiences.  I have had the honor of working with three other talented students from the University of British Columbia as well as with two friendly and intelligent Mozilla employees in the Jupyter Notebook project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is a Jupyter Notebook, and why should you really care?&lt;br /&gt;
Well, the Jupyter Notebook is an electronic document that can contain Python code as well as flexible human-readable text such as paragraphs, comments, figures, equations, etc.  The code within these documents can be executed and analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main challenges I have overcome during this experience so far is learning to function within and adapting to the somewhat distributed working environment.  Previous assignments I’ve worked on were with a local team of developers usually in person.  People could be called or messaged and then ideas could be bounced off each other on whiteboards, over a cup of coffee or even on the same computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new approach has team members all over Canada working together (British Columbia, Ontario, Nova Scotia) as well as internationally (England).  The first and most obvious obstacle is that with each different area, there is a different time zone.  When scheduling meetings or Skype calls, it is common to find a reasonable time, taking into consideration the up-to-nine-hour time difference.  Outside of these scheduled weekly meetings, we often find ourselves communicating via IRC or Skype, both platforms which I am familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jupyter Project uses many different technologies – some I have used before and others not so much.  The languages include JavaScript and Python – the former I have used for mere hours (but am currently learning) and the latter I have not used since my first year.  Ramping up was a significant challenge, as the time spent studying syntax and language structure put me even further behind my teammates.  I often felt like the least useful member of the team as the other students were much better versed in the aforementioned technologies.  In spite of this, however, after the initial ramping period I felt much more comfortable working on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be asking, “Well I know what the notebooks are, so what is your team doing?”  Our team is currently working on various add-ons for the Jupyter Notebook – extensions that will be released open-source and accessible to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project was a simple extension that would allow Jupyter Notebook files to be uploaded to GitHub’s gist platform.  Specifically, the content from the Notebook (code and text) would be uploaded to the authenticated user’s GitHub account via OAuth2 for safe keeping.  During our Toronto code sprint in January, we laid down the foundation for this extension.  The main goal for the meeting was to successfully implement a new button in the JavaScript front-end, and to link it to the Python back-end server (where the Jupyter Notebook was running) for processing.  Knowing I had limited knowledge in JavaScript at the time, I took it upon myself to handle much of the back-end Python code instead.  As I had previously studied OAuth2 in a Computer Security class at my university (ECE568), most of the APIs were familiar.  For those that don’t know, OAuth2 is a protocol used by a client (our server acts as a client to GitHub) and a server (the GitHub server offering the OAuth2 service) to allow secure access to an authenticated user’s private information.  Specifically, the user is redirected to GitHub, where they specify which services to allow us (the client) to use.  After authentication, GitHub will then comply with our requests (in this case, uploading the notebook contents as a Gist) on the user’s behalf.  After sifting through the many pages of the GitHub API documentation, I was able to independently implement the handshaking and authentication process between GitHub and our server.  However, I got stuck with formatting the notebook content which was formatted in JSON.  After spending several hours trying to figure out why my GitHub call would return with a ‘404’ error, I was at a loss.  At that point, knowing nothing about JavaScript or JSON, sought out help from my teammates who were eager to jump in and lend a hand.  Turns out there is a bizarre function call in JavaScript called “JSON.stringify” that ended up solving my issue.  With the whole team working together, we were able to get the extension out and it is now available via ‘pip’ or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mozilla/jupyter-notebook-gist&#34;&gt;https://github.com/mozilla/jupyter-notebook-gist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our second extension was an add-on for Apache Spark integration.  Apache Spark is a framework for cluster computing – a system where distributed machines can be used together to perform large computations.  It is very useful when data processing, something that Mozilla would definitely use to process large volumes of Firefox usage information.  If, within the Jupyter Notebook, an Apache Spark job was ongoing, we wanted to provide a progress bar.  Unfortunately this task had just gotten off the ground as the university’s Reading Week began, and I had already made plans to be out of the country.  I kept tabs on the progress (IRC) during that week, but sadly did not have time to make significant contributions.  Upon return, I tried to quickly ramp up, but to little avail. Apache Spark does not like to run on native Windows, so I installed VirtualBox with Ubuntu 15.04 to get it working.  Only after much debugging and installing, did I realize that all the tasks for the Apache project were taken and/or in progress by another team member.  The feeling of insignificance returned, but after expressing my concern to the Mozilla team lead, he mentioned that it might be better to get started on the next project which would soon be fleshed out and discussed.  At the end of our meeting, he mentioned someone around the office was looking for C++ assistance, which is my area of expertise so I will definitely follow up on that as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That pretty much sums up where I am now at currently in the project.  I definitely enjoy working with everyone, and my mentors are very intelligent, open and approachable individuals.  I feel like working in an open-source environment provides me with unrestricted access to the world’s knowledge, and even someone like myself can share everything that I have learned.  Being able to see people happily using what I have worked on is such an amazing pleasure and honor for me, as a software developer.  I hope that I will be able to continue to make a difference both in the Jupyter Notebook project, and in future endeavours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While UCOSP will soon come to a close, the journey into the world of open-source is a never ending road of exploration, learning and sharing.  Mozilla is a wonderful company with many wonderful people.  It would be a dream to be given opportunities to work with them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Generate UML Diagram of Models in Django Project</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/01/12/how-to-generate-uml-diagram-of-models-in-django-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 11:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2016/01/12/how-to-generate-uml-diagram-of-models-in-django-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;(An experience report from Yorie Nakayama)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are developing with python on Django, or on any frameworks that employ
the MVC (Model-View-Controller) paradigm, you might come across whether there
is a way to easily visualize all the models and their dependency relationships
in your application as a diagram. Models are central to most applications using
MVC, and being able to glance at the structure of models and their
relationships to each other greatly helps any developer beginning to hack on
the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I worked with Reviewboard, a Django-based web app for doing code reviews,
for my UCOSP, one of the first things I did was to generate a UML diagram of
the models in the project using an extension package for Django called
django-extensions. The diagram would let the students, who are new to the
project, to see the overall picture of the models, and also let the mentors
easily explain how some models are related to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will provide a step-by-step instruction on generating a UML
diagram of a Django application using django-extensions. Similar tools
also exist for other MVC frameworks, such as railroady gem for Ruby on
Rails, or phuml for PHP (not limited to CodeIgniter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-install-dependencies:34163b606f8a2eecb59d56bdb3d8dde5&#34;&gt;1. Install Dependencies.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For python, you need to install either pydot or pygraphviz as a python
interface of the graph visualization library called graphviz. Either will be
fine as far as django-extensions is concerned. I went with pydot because I had
a trouble installing pygraphviz. If you choose to go with pygraphviz, you can
ignore this step and resume from step 2 after installing pygraphviz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install pyparsing==1.5.7
  
pip install graphviz
  
pip install pydot
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The version is specified on pyparsing installation because pydot is not
compatible with newer (&amp;gt;=2.x.x) versions of pyparsing. I recommend that
graphviz is installed before pydot to avoid an issue where pydot is not
able to find graphviz executable. A similar installation issue may also
occur with pygraphviz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-install-django-extensions:34163b606f8a2eecb59d56bdb3d8dde5&#34;&gt;2. Install django-extensions.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Django-extensions provides various tools that could help development of
Django applications such as enhanced shell, or UML diagram generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;pip install django-extensions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-enable-django-extensions-in-your-project:34163b606f8a2eecb59d56bdb3d8dde5&#34;&gt;3. Enable django-extensions in your project.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under your Django project directory, open the file setting.py with a
text editor. Within the settings, you should find a python list called
INSTALLED_APPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Append &amp;#8216;django_extensions&amp;#8217; to the list and save. Then you can use the functionalities that django-extensions provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-generate-the-uml-diagram:34163b606f8a2eecb59d56bdb3d8dde5&#34;&gt;4. Generate the UML diagram.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a command shell, go to the Django project directory, and execute the
following command to generate your diagram of all models in the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python manage.py graph\_models -a -o myapp\_models.png&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The -a flag specifies to include all apps listed in INSTALLED_APPS for
diagram generation. The output path is relative to the project root
directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide that your project does not need django-extensions, you can
simply remove &amp;#8216;django_extensions&amp;#8217; from INSTALLED_APPS in settings.py.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a UML diagram for your models, you can easily see the overall
picture of the data organization in your application. Hopefully this
diagram could help a new member on a Django project to find where to
start with the development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212; Yorie Nakayama&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Ready for the New Year</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2015/12/15/getting-ready-for-the-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2015/12/15/getting-ready-for-the-new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we prepare for the next group of students who will start in January, we are seeing some turnover in the project offerings for UCOSP, so I&amp;#8217;d like to welcome the newcomers and thank the project mentors from the past term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project mentors for Waterbear, CodeIgniter, and Mylyn are all based in Vancouver which makes it more difficult to attend a code sprint in Toronto.  It has been great working with Dethe, James and Sam, and I hope we will have a chance to work with you again in the future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also saying goodbye a long-term project: Phonegap.  Tim Windsor has moved to a different job and is not able to supervise students this term.  Tim has been a terrific mentor over several years, and it would be a great pleasure to work with him again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are welcoming two new projects this term, both from Mozilla: &lt;span class=&#34;&#34;&gt;Jupyter Notebooks for Data Analysis, and Code Coverage Explorer.  I&amp;#8217;m excited to see what students will do on both of these projects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board projects from the fall</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2014/02/review-board-projects-from-the-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2014 10:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2014/02/review-board-projects-from-the-fall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2014/02/12/ucosp-fall-2013-student-demos/&#34;&gt;demos&lt;/a&gt; that students working on ReviewBoard created in the fall term.  Great work!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.5em;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter 2014 Sprint</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2014/02/winter-2014-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2014 11:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2014/02/winter-2014-sprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The UCOSP sprint for Winter 2014 is underway. This term UCOSP is in rainy Palo Alto California at Facebook HQ. This term we have 48 Canadian students from 22 universities contributing to 27 open source projects. This term UCOSP has joined up with [](&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/OpenAcademyProgram&#34;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/OpenAcademyProgram&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Facebook Open Academy&amp;rdquo;) program which adds another 200 students from a dozen US, European, and Asian schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bishop&amp;#8217;s University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brock University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polytechnic school of Montreal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simon Fraser University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thompson Rivers University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Alberta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of British Columbia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Calgary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Guelph&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Manitoba&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of New Brunswick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Ottawa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Sherbrooke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Toronto&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Toronto Mississauga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Waterloo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University of Western Ontario&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wilfrid Laurier University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;York University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App Inventor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blackberry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CodeBender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Freeseer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GeoGit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GeoTrellis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HVVM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JTS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KDevelop (Ruby support)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kotlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mozilla Marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open Stack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prediction.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ReviewBoard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Umple&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waterbear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikimedia &amp;#8211; Cron&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the code sprint everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparing for Fall 2013</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2013/05/preparing-for-fall-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 15:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2013/05/preparing-for-fall-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While students are enjoying a summer away from school (or at least that&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;d like to think you are doing), we are putting all the pieces in place for UCOSP next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a very successful year with students from 25 Canadian universities participating. The enthusiasm and energy that students and mentors brought to the code sprints in Waterloo and Menlo Park was fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently learned that Google will once again be our primary sponsor. Without their continued support, UCOSP could not have grown in the program that we have today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the fall, we are thrilled to announce that Mozilla will be hosting the sprint in downtown Toronto. They have a great space and lots of expertise on site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still working on plans for the January code sprint, but we hope to team up again with the great program that Jay Borenstein from Stanford is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also still working on finalizing the set of projects for next year, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are a CS student at a Canadian university talk to your department to learn how to apply to participate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2012/03/review-board-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 21:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2012/03/review-board-update-3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Steven MacLeod &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2012/03/26/ucosp-blog-post/&#34;&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My experience with UCOSP has been very fulfilling thus far. I’ve met a lot of great people, and have enjoyed working on the Review Board project more than I ever would have expected. One of my favourite aspects of the program is the feeling that your contributions are significant; The code you write is distributed to and executed by real users. This is in stark contrast to the usual work which is done in university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCOSP gives you the chance to work on some really interesting projects, and I’d like to give on overview of what I’ve been working on thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;review-bot:05eba46d420c16cf63cdce2518bca79f&#34;&gt;Review Bot:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main project I’ve taken on for UCOSP is something I’ve dubbed “Review Bot”. The goal of Review Bot is to automatically execute static analysis tools on code that has been posted for review on Review Board. Basically, it will review code using external programs, and then post any issues it finds to Review Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking through the design, and receiving feedback from the community looking to automate static analysis using Review Board, I came up with a plan of attack. My initial aspirations for Review Bot are illustrated below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1577&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34; style=&#34;width: 610px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/reviewbot1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1577&#34; title=&#34;Imagined Review Bot&#34; src=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/reviewbot1.png?w=600&amp;h=514&#34; alt=&#34;Review Bot of my dreams&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;514&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    How Review Bot was envisioned &amp;#8211; Warning: Imagination Required
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, that’s a code reviewing, go-go-gadget armed robot with a jet-pack. It reviews code written in any language, and can solve the halting problem. I considered allowing it to review its own code, but the risk of it becoming sentient and enslaving the human race was too great. But in all seriousness, I planned to make a highly versatile code reviewing bot, which other developers could extend to support the static analysis tools of their liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it can be hard to properly scope a project when dealing with an unfamiliar code base. I quickly realised this as I ventured deeper into Review Board’s API and extension support. Once I’d begun working through the implementation of Review Bot, it became apparent that my project was going to be a lot of work! Review Board lacked some of the features necessary to support the Review Bot I had envisioned. My first order of business was to fix this; I set out to extend the Web API and expand the feature set of the extension system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review Board’s extension system is powerful, young, and light in the documentation department. The lack of online documentation was a little worrisome at first, but prior developers had commented their code very well. Combine this with some very knowledgeable and helpful mentors, and hacking on extensions proved to be a blast. Even though Review Board is a mature code base, I was able to work on something fresh and exciting; you don’t have to worry about backwards compatibility when the feature isn’t in use yet. My time spent with the extension system has given me the expertise needed to document it, and my beginner’s guide for future developers is nearing completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this related development has kept Review Bot on the back-burner for a lot of the term. To give you an idea of Review Bot’s current state, here is an artists rendering of the progress I’ve made:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1578&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34; style=&#34;width: 610px;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/reviewbot2.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1578&#34; title=&#34;Current State of Review Bot&#34; src=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/reviewbot2.png?w=600&amp;h=514&#34; alt=&#34;What Review Bot can accomplish at the moment&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;514&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    What Review Bot can accomplish at the moment
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All right, I might be selling myself a little short with that picture. While it is true that Review Bot can’t actually analyse any code yet, progress should be quick now that Review Board has the features needed to support it. By the end of the term Review Bot should be automatically analysing Python code with the pep8 style checker. Some features, such as allowing tools to analyse the entire code base and not just the modified files, had to be dropped – but I’m still happy with how the final product will look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;in-closing:05eba46d420c16cf63cdce2518bca79f&#34;&gt;In Closing:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really can’t stress how happy I am to be participating in this program, and I recommend it to any students given the opportunity to participate. I’d like to thank the UCOSP steering committee for organizing everything. Also, a very big thank you to the Review Board mentors: Christian Hammond, David Trowbridge, and Mike Conley. These guys have made this experience awesome, and I really appreciate all the time and effort they have committed to the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for bearing with my artistic “ability”,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven MacLeod&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UMPLE October 2011 Update</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2011/10/umple-october-2011-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 17:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2011/10/umple-october-2011-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Umple project is advancing rapidly this semester with three UCOSP students making major contributions in parallel with other contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UCOSP students are have tackled some smaller features and bugs, and are now working on a couple of long-standing major issues: Generating comprehensive and useful error messages, and getting rid of certain syntax oddities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lethbridge, the project mentor, just posted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tims-ideas.blogspot.com/2011/10/umple-status-and-recent-progress.html&#34; title=&#34;blog post&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; that covers the recent work in technical detail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked each of the three UCOSP students to highlight what they have been learning and doing, what they have liked about the project so far, and what improvements they think they would like to see to how Umple is developed or the how UCOSP program is run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Joshua Horacsek:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I&amp;#8217;ve been working on making Umple more user-friendly. I&amp;#8217;ve been reworking the way Umple handles lexical and semantic errors, hopefully making it more robust, and ultimately more useable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favourite part of Umple isn&amp;#8217;t necessarily what the project aims to accomplish, but rather how the different components of Umple are built, what they&amp;#8217;re built with, and how they interact. That&amp;#8217;s not to say the idea of a model based language isn&amp;#8217;t interesting, it&amp;#8217;s just that Umple&amp;#8217;s a fairly large project, and it&amp;#8217;s pretty fun to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve learned how to look at a fairly large project with multiple different components, and break it down into components that I understand. I&amp;#8217;ve also learned the benefit of test driven development, and the headaches and time it saves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, I have two primary goals. The first is to get Umple to a point where it produces concise error feedback for a wide variety of input. The second goal is tied to code generation from an Umple model. Currently, Umple can generate code for various languages such as Java, PHP and Ruby. If I have time I&amp;#8217;d like to extend it to generate SQL models, and if not, at least there&amp;#8217;ll be some partial code for a future UCOSP project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, I can&amp;#8217;t really see what either UCOSP or Umple could be doing better for UCOSP students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Alvina Lee:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working on a feature which allows umple to generate comments before classes. I made patches for issues regarding lazy keywords for attributes in generating singleton classes as well as automatically changing associations from 1 to 0..1 (issue 26).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that I get to learn new things and make use of computer science related stuff I&amp;#8217;ve used before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am learning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Using JUnit on larger projects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Learning to work with other people who do not live in the same area on the same project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Learning to use new technology that I am not familiar with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Learning about UML&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of this term, I will have some involvement with error parsing and have commenting for attributes and other objects implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the project could be doing better: Umple has included some video tutorials. While I appreciate the fact that they are offering help in setting up the developing environment, I do not like video tutorials because I have to wait to download them, and I dislike the format because it is harder to skip around to relevant sections if I am already familiar with what is being explained in some parts of the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From Joel Hobson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Joel Hobson, and this is my first blog post for the UCOSP project and Umple. I&amp;#8217;m currently working on two main tasks for Umple &amp;#8211; First, I&amp;#8217;m working on adding a debug mode for developers that shows which JET templates generate specific code, in order to make it easier to add new languages to Umple. My other main task is fixing the various bugs regarding whitespace. Umple is currently finicky about whitespace, and code that programmers would expect to be valid, such as class X { attributeName=&amp;#8221;&amp;#8221;; } causes problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve never had the opportunity to work on a large software project before, and I&amp;#8217;ve greatly enjoyed the experience. Umple is a very interesting project, and I feel it could be extremely useful for large software projects when it becomes a little more mature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on Umple, I&amp;#8217;ve learned a great deal about test-driven development. I had a vague understanding of the concept before, but now that I&amp;#8217;ve actually used it I can see just how useful it is. I&amp;#8217;ve also gained experience working with Apache Ant and Subversion, and have a much better idea of how contribution to open source projects works. The biggest challenge so far was getting it to build correctly on my system. Even now, I have some difficulty with errors in the build process, but overall things are going fairly smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goals for the project include finishing the debug mode and fixing the whitespace bugs, as well as writing Umple extensions for various text editors and fixing random bugs, time permitting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review Board team climbs the learning curve</title>
      <link>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2011/10/review-board-team-climbs-the-learning-curve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 15:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://haruute0.github.io/2009-2010/uncategorized/2011/10/review-board-team-climbs-the-learning-curve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a great description of the steps students took to getting fully up to speed and moving forward on their projects on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://reviewboardstudents.wordpress.com/2011/10/02/ucosp-blog-post-october-2nd-2011/&#34; title=&#34;Review Board blog&#34;&gt;Review Board blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m glad to hear that the code sprint was worthwhile!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>